[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
大卫·马兰：好的
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是CS50的S介绍用PYTHON编程
This is CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python.
我的名字是David Malan 这周我们主要关注循环 这是Python中的这一功能
My name is David Malan, and this week we focus on loops, this ability in Python
以及许多其他编程语言来一次又一次地做一些事情
and a lot of other programming languages to do something again and again,
这是一种循环
a cycle of sorts.
让我们看看我们能不能从激励
And let's see if we can't begin by motivating
这就是为什么我们有这种能力 使用这些循环循环地做事情
exactly why we have this ability to do things cyclically using these loops.
我将在这里继续 打开VS代码
I'm going to go ahead here and open up VS Code.
在我的终端窗口中 让我们继续
And in my terminal window, let's go ahead
并通过代码cat.py进行创建 这是一个像猫一样发出猫叫声的Python程序
and create via code cat.py, a Python program that meows like a cat.
我将在这个代码选项卡中继续 可能非常简单
And I'm going to go ahead here in this Code tab, and very simply, perhaps,
我将从使用打印来实现这个CAT开始
I'm going to start by implementing this cat just by using print.
我们要让这只猫不发出声音
We're going to have this cat not make audible sounds,
但只要在屏幕上打印三次猫咪、猫咪、猫咪就可以了
but just print meow, meow, meow on the screen three times.
我想我能做到的最简单的方法就是打印猫咪一次
Well, I think the simplest way I can do this is just to print meow once,
并再次打印猫咪 并在屏幕上打印最后一次猫咪
and to print meow again, and to print meow one last time on the screen.
现在让我转到我的终端窗口 让我运行cat.py的Python
And now let me go down to my terminal window, let me run Python of cat.py,
进来 然后叫 叫 叫
Enter, and meow, meow, meow.
好了 这个程序起作用了
All right, so this program works.
如果我的目标是让猫叫三次 这个程序确实有效
This program indeed works if my goal is to get the cat to meow three times.
让我向你求婚 只是为了帮助我们
And let me propose, just to help us wrap our minds around
计算机内部发生了什么 让我们
what's going on inside of the computer, let
我建议我们考虑这个流程图
me propose that we consider this flowchart.
所以像以前一样 我们有这个流程图
So as before, we have this flowchart that
从这个椭圆形开始 意思就是从这里开始阅读
starts with this oval, which just means start reading here.
然后注意 它通过箭头发出猫叫声 然后停止
And then notice, it goes via arrows to a meow, meow, meow, and then it stops.
这是完全正确的 老实说 它非常简单
It's perfectly correct, and honestly, it's wonderfully simple,
但我敢说 不管怎样 我们还是可以找出我的代码的错误
but I daresay we can find fault with my code nonetheless.
为什么我的代码可以说是设计得很差？
Why is my code arguably poorly designed?
现在 答案将是某种程度上的循环
Now the answer is going to be loops in some way,
但让我们看看我们能不能用什么方式
but let's see if we can identify in what way
在某种意义上 代码实际上设计得很差
the code is actually poorly designed in some sense.
让我们看看
Let's see.
任何想法
Any thoughts.
亚历克斯？
Alex?
观众：好的
AUDIENCE: OK.
所以 我的意思是 重复同样的动作三次甚至更多
So, I mean, repeating the same action like three times or even more
不是一个好习惯
is not a good habit.
大卫·马兰：是的 我只是在重复我自己
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I'm just repeating myself.
老实说 这没什么大不了的
And honestly, it's not that big a deal.
如果我们在这里回到我的代码 我真的做了一件坏事吗
If we go back to my code here, am I really doing such a bad thing
只要打印三次猫叫 猫叫 猫叫就可以了？
by just printing meow, meow, meow three times?
不完全是 但让我们考虑一下这一点的逻辑扩展
Not really, but let's consider the logical extension of this.
假设我想叫四次、五次、50次或500次
Suppose I wanted to meow four times or five times or 50 times or 500 times.
你真的认为 即使你以前从来没有编程过
Do you really think, even if you've never programmed before,
这个问题的解决方案真的是点击复制粘贴50次吗？
is the solution to this problem really going to be to hit copy-paste 50 times?
大概不会吧
Like probably not.
我们或许可以做得更好
We can probably do better than that.
在这一点上 除了丑陋之外
And beyond it just being ugly at that point,
有这么多行相同的代码 只是
having so many lines of identical code, just
想象一下 如果您想要更改代码
imagine if you wanted to change the code.
也许我改变主意了 我不想养猫 我想养狗
Maybe I change my mind and I don't want to make a cat, I want to make a dog.
所以现在它不得不多次说汪汪 汪汪 汪汪
So now it has to say woof, woof, woof multiple times.
现在我必须在50个不同的地方改变这一点
Now I have to change that in 50 different places.
是的 当然 我可以找到并替换
And yeah, sure, I could do find and replace,
但得了吧 就像我们现在是程序员一样
but come on, like we're programmers now, there's
一定有更好的方法而不是重复我们自己
got to be a better way than just repeating ourselves.
所以我敢打赌 如果我们稍微考虑一下 我们可以做得更好
So I bet we can do better than that if we think about a little
我们如何构建这个项目就更加困难了
harder how we go about structuring this program.
只要我们稍微增加一点词汇量 我们就能做到这一点
And we can do that if we augment our vocabulary just a little bit.
事实证明 在Python和其他语言中
It turns out in Python, and in other languages,
还有一个关键字叫做While
too, there's a keyword called while.
虽然这是我们可以表达所谓的循环的一种方式
And while is one way that we can express what's called a loop,
一段代码 它将一次又一次地做一些事情--
a block of code that's going to do something again and again and again--
0倍 1倍 2倍 50倍 想要多少倍就多少倍
0 times, 1 time, 2 times, 50 times, as many times as we want.
而是把细节留给我们
But while rather leaves to us the particulars
关于我们如何一次又一次地表达自己去做某事
of how we express ourselves to do something again and again.
所以让我回到VS代码 让我提议我这样做
So let me go back over to VS Code here and let me propose that I do this.
While是一个允许我一遍又一遍地问问题的结构
While is a construct that allows me to ask a question again and again.
任何时候我们看到一个问题 它都是
And any time we've seen a question, it's been
以布尔表达式的形式 问题的答案是
in the form of a Boolean expression, a question to which the answer is
对或错
true or false.
我怎么能这么做呢？
Well, how could I do this?
我怎么能打印三次猫咪 问三次问题呢？
How could I print out meow three times and ask three times a question
答案是真的还是假的？
to which the answer is true or false?
好吧 如果我数一数呢？
Well, what if I did some counting?
就像真的在我手指上一样
Like literally on my fingers.
如果我试着从三个倒数 我想猫叫三次
And if I'm trying to count maybe down from three, I want to meow three times,
我可以竖起三根手指 然后我就会叫了
I can put three fingers up and I can meow.
然后我可以把其中一根手指放下来 然后猫叫
And then I can put like one of the fingers down and then meow.
我可以把其中一根手指放下来 然后我就能猫叫了
And I can put one of the fingers down and I can meow.
把其中一根手指放下
Put one of the fingers down.
也许我每次猫叫的时候都会问这个问题
And maybe the question I can ask every time I meow
是 我还能竖起手指吗？
is, do I have any fingers up still?
我还能竖起手指吗？
Do I have any fingers up still?
如果答案是真的 那就继续前进
And if the answer is true, keep going.
如果答案是假的 请停止
If the answer is false, stop.
那么 我如何将其转换为代码呢？
So how can I translate that to code?
好的 一旦我们添加了这个While关键字--
Well, once we've added this while keyword--
我认为我们已经拥有了所有的构建块 让我提议我这样做
I think we have all the building blocks already, let me propose that I do this.
让我提议我给自己一个变量
Let me propose that I give myself a variable.
我会把它叫做i代表整数 但我想怎么叫都行
And I'll call it i for integer, but I could call it anything I want,
我要把它初始化为3
and I'm going to initialize it to 3.
然后我将使用Python的这个新功能 同时
Then I'm going to use this new feature of Python, while,
我要问一个问题 答案必须是真的或假的
and I'm going to ask a question, the answer to which must be true or false.
我要说 虽然我不等于0
And I'm going to say, while i does not equal 0.
所以我要问这个问题 虽然我不等于0 但请做以下操作
So I'm going to ask the question, while i does not equal 0, do the following.
请注意该行末尾的冒号
Notice the colon at the end of the line.
注意我的凹痕
Notice my indentation.
就像函数一样 就像条件句一样
And just like with functions, just like with conditionals,
缩进您只想作为另一件事的一部分执行的行
you indent the lines that you only want to execute as part of this other thing.
当我不等于0的时候 我想做什么？
What do I want to do while i does not equal 0?
好吧 我想我只想猫叫一声
Well, I think I just want to meow.
但仅仅编写这段代码是不够的
But it's not enough just to write this code.
如果我现在非常危险地运行cat.py的Python并按Enter键
If I were to very dangerously run Python of cat.py and hit Enter right now,
银幕上可能会发生什么？
what might happen on the screen?
不管你以前是否编程过
Whether you've programmed before or not.
为什么这是一件潜在的非常糟糕的事情？
Why is this a very bad thing potentially?
它不会弄坏东西 但它可能会失去对我电脑的控制
It's not going to break things, but it might lose control of my computer
不知怎么的
somehow.
有什么想法吗？
Any thoughts?
喂 提莫？
Yeah, Timo?
观众：嗨
AUDIENCE: Hi.
我想它会继续输出meow 因为i总是等于3
I think it's going to continue to print out meow since i is always equal to 3
而while永远是真的
and the while is always true.
大卫·马兰：是的 没错
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
如果我把i初始化为3--也就是说 在第1行设置它等于3
If I'm initializing i to 3-- that is, setting it equal to 3 on line 1,
那么我会问 虽然i不等于0
then I'm asking the question, while i does not equal 0,
这是真的 它不等于0
and that's going to be true, it does not equal 0,
它显然等于3 打印meow
it obviously equals 3, print meow.
while循环的工作方式是Python解释器
And the way a while loop works is that the Python interpreter just
不停地来回移动
keeps going back and forth.
它从第一行到第二行 然后到第三行
It goes from line 1 to line 2, then to line 3,
然后它回到第二行再次提问
and then it goes back to line 2 to ask the question again.
如果答案仍然为真 则转到第3行
If the answer is still true, it goes to line 3.
然后它回到第2行
It then goes back to line 2.
如果答案仍然为真 则返回到第3行
If the answer is still true, it goes back to line 3.
根据Timo的观点 如果你永远不改变i的值
And to Timo's point, if you're never actually changing the value of i,
它总是3 你会一直循环下去
it's always 3, you're just going to be looping literally forever,
这是一个偶然的无限循环
and this is an accidental infinite loop.
所以我们得聪明点
So we've got to be smarter than that.
我不会按回车键因为我不想
And I'm not going to hit Enter because I don't
我想失去对我的电脑的控制 这样它就
want to lose control over my computer here such that it's
永远打印出喵
printing out meow forever.
幸运的是 如果你真的这么做了
Fortunately, if you ever do do that and you find yourself
在意外无限循环中 Control-C表示取消或中断
in an accidental infinite loop, Control-C for cancel or interrupt
会成为你的朋友
is going to be your friend.
如果你似乎失去了控制 你不需要重新启动
If you ever seem to lose control, you don't need to reboot
或者关掉电脑
or turn off the computer.
您可以在终端窗口中按Control-C
You can just hit Control-C in your terminal window
这可能会解决问题
and that will likely fix it.
好吧 那我每次喵喵叫完之后 要做什么呢？
All right, well what do I want to do, then, after meowing each time?
我想我在这里想做的是这样的
I think what I'd like to do here is maybe something like this.
让我把i更新为等于当前值减1
Let me update i to equal whatever the current value is minus 1 here--
哎呀 对不起
whoops, sorry.
减去1
Minus 1.
所以如果每次迭代时i--
So if i on each iteration--
我在更新我 让我少一个
I'm updating i to be one less, one less, one less,
它最终应该会达到0 在这一点上 9.2%的S问题的答案
it should eventually hit 0, at which point the answer to 9.2's question
现在将是假的
will now be false.
因此 让我们看看这是否奏效
So let's see if this works.
我将转到我的终端窗口 运行cat.py的Python
I'm going to go down to my terminal window and run Python of cat.py,
我真的收到了三声猫叫
and I indeed get three meows.
为什么？
Why?
因为如果你愿意的话 我已经把它像一台软件里的机器一样连起来了
Because I've wired this up like a machine in software, if you will.
我设定i等于3 然后我继续问这个问题
I've set i equal to 3, then I keep asking this question.
但是我一直在转动齿轮 我一直在改变变量的值
But I keep turning the gears, I keep changing the value of the variable
以确保最终它实际上是
to make sure that ultimately it is actually
被递减--也就是说 递减1 直到我们最终达到0
being decremented-- that is, decreased by 1 until we eventually hit 0.
现在对于那些认为我更生动一些的人来说
Now for those of you who think I'm a little more graphically,
让我调出一个我们通常使用的流程图
let me pull up one of our usual flow charts.
这只是完全相同的事情的图形表示
This is just a representation graphically of the exact same thing.
注意正在发生的事情
Notice what's happening.
我首先启动程序 然后将i初始化为3
I first start the program, and then I initialize i to 3,
然后我问我的第一个问题
and then I ask the first of my questions.
再说一次 钻石总是代表着问题
Again, the diamonds always represent questions.
答案将是真的或假的
And the answer is going to be true or false.
我不等于0吗？
Does i not equal 0?
嗯 它不是 它等于3
Well, it doesn't, it equals 3.
所以 如果我遵循真实的路线 我就会猫叫
So if I follow the true line, I meow.
然后我沿着这个箭头 我把i更新为等于i减1
And then I follow this arrow, and I update i to equal i minus 1.
在故事的这一点上 我大概在数学上等于2
At this point in the story, i presumably equals 2 mathematically.
我跟着箭头走
I follow the arrow.
这就是循环
And there's the loop.
这就是为什么能以图形方式看到这一点是很好的
This is why it's nice to see this graphically,
也许是因为你可以从字面上看到循环来回
perhaps because you can literally see the loop back and forth.
现在我再问一遍这个问题
Now I ask the question again.
2不等于0吗？
Does 2 not equal 0?
嗯 它不等于0 它是2 所以我们再叫一次
Well, it does not equal 0, it's 2, so we meow again.
我们把i从2改为1
We change i from 2 to 1.
那么 1不等于0吗？
Well, does 1 not equal 0?
显然1不是0 所以我们再猫咪一次
Well obviously 1 is not 0, so we meow again.
我们又一次减少了I 我现在是0
We decrement i again. i is now 0.
0不等于0吗？
Does 0 not equal 0?
不 它等于0 所以答案是假的 我们停止
No, it equals 0, so the answer is false and we stop.
所以在那里 也许比我们以前的任何流程图都更有说服力
So there, perhaps more so than any of our flowcharts before,
你真的看到项目内部发生的事情的结构了吗？
do you really see the structure of what's happening inside of the program?
你不必养成制作这些图表的习惯
And you don't have to get into the habit of making these charts
或创建这些图表 但只是作为第一次通过
or creating these charts, but just as a first pass at what's
进入计算机内部 这确实是一种将其可视化的方法
going on inside of the computer, that's indeed one way to visualize it instead.
好吧 让我提议 像往常一样 有很多不同的方式
Well let me propose that, like always, there's many different ways
来解决这个问题
to solve this problem.
假设你只是喜欢有一点不同的想法
And suppose you just like to think a little differently.
也许你不喜欢从3开始 然后倒数到0
Maybe you don't like starting at 3 and then counting down to 0.
为什么？
Why?
也许你只是大脑不是这样工作的
Maybe you're just brain doesn't work that way
而且你更喜欢倒数 而不是倒数
and you prefer to count up instead of down.
完全没问题
Totally fine.
让我继续更改我的代码 将i设置为等于1 而不是3
Let me go ahead and change my code here to set i equal to 1 instead of 3.
在这里 让我改变一下我的逻辑
And here, let me just change my logic.
而不是检查是否不等于0 比如
Rather than checking for not equal to 0, like maybe
你不喜欢这样想 不是因为这有点令人困惑
you don't like thinking in terms of not because it's a little confusing,
也可能是 让我们检查一下 i是否小于或等于3
and it might be, let's just check that i is less than or equal to 3.
所以我们会说得更清楚一些
So we'll be a little more explicit.
我们会从1数到3 每次打印猫咪
We'll count from 1 up through 3, each time printing meow,
但我需要在这里更改这条线
but I'm going to need to change this line here.
让我看看能不能叫人帮我换一下线路
Let me see if we can't call on someone to change line for me.
如何将第4行更改为与从1开始向上计数一致
How do I want to change line 4 to be consistent with counting from 1 up
从3点到3点？
to and through 3?
观众：每次你猫咪叫 我都会加1
AUDIENCE: I would be plus 1 every time you meow.
大卫·马兰：是的 确实如此
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
在本例中 我们想要加1而不是减1
In this case, we want to add one not subtract 1.
事实上 如果你仔细想想 这两部电影的结局可能会非常糟糕
And in fact, if you think about this, this 2 could end very poorly.
如果你从1开始数 然后一直减1 减1
If you start counting at 1 and you keep subtracting 1, subtracting 1,
减去1 我想我们会发现我们自己
subtracting 1, I think we're going to find ourselves
有同样的问题 那就是我们永远不会停止 因为我们
with the same problem, which is that we're never going to stop because we're
会变得越来越消极 而不是站起来
going to keep getting more and more negative as opposed to ever getting up
到数字3
to the number 3.
所以我认为你是对的 我需要把这个改成i等于i加1
So I think you're right, I need to change this to be i equals i plus 1.
现在 为了清楚起见 请注意等号
And now notice just for clarity, too, the equal sign
也是我们从右到左的赋值运算符
is, again, our assignment operator from right to left.
从逻辑上讲 这可能会让你感到奇怪
Logically, this might otherwise strike you as strange.
比如我怎么能等于自己加1呢？
Like how can i equal itself plus 1?
除非你从右向左执行这段代码
Well, it doesn't until you execute this code from right to left.
你给i加1或者i减1 然后更新i的值
You add 1 to i or you subtract 1 from i, and then you update the value of i
左边即
on the left.
赋值将值从右向左复制
The assignment copies the value from the right to the left.
我还能怎么做
Well, how else might I do this?
好吧 我会说大多数程序员 更普遍的计算机科学家
Well, I will say that most programmers, computer scientists more generally,
往往从0开始计数
tend to start counting from 0.
这是一个惯例 它实际上有好处
It's a convention and it actually has upsides even
在Python和其他语言中 一般来说
in Python and other languages where generally speaking,
从0开始计数是件好事
it's a good thing to start counting from 0
而不是像我们在现实世界中那样从1开始计数
instead of counting like we might in the real world from 1.
让我们现在就通过这项公约
Let's go ahead and adopt that convention now.
让我把i设为0 现在我需要做一个改变
Let me set i equal to 0, and I need to make a change now.
注意 如果我不改变我的逻辑 这个程序就会有bug
Notice, if I don't change my logic, this program just became buggy.
这只猫有一只虫子
The cat has a bug.
如果我照现在的样子跑 它会叫四次
It's now meowing four times if I run it as is.
但最简单的解决办法是改变我的不等式
But the easiest fix here would be to change my inequality
是这个 小于而不是小于或等于
to be this, less than instead of less than or equal to.
现在我从0开始 但我会一直到3
Now I'm starting at 0, but I'm going up to but not through 3.
即使这可能 在我们目前看到的所有事情中
And even though this might, of all the things we've seen thus far,
似乎是最不熟悉的 我们大多数人可能从1开始 2 然后3
seem maybe the least familiar, most of us might start at 1, 2, then 3,
这是一个好习惯 从0开始
it's a good habit to get into now, start at 0,
最终达到但不是通过你所关心的价值
and go up to but not through the value that you care about ultimately,
3在这种情况下
3 in this case here.
好吧 让我把这里的东西弄紧一点
Well, let me tighten things up a bit here.
这不仅能解决我的数数问题
Not only will this now fix my counting problem,
它现在的叫声是预期的3倍
it now meows 3 times as expected, there's
一种更简洁的方式来表示i等于i
a more succinct way to express i equals i
加1 这是因为这是一个很流行的代码
plus 1, and this, is because it's such a popular thing to do in code.
你可以说i+等于1 就是这样
You can instead just say i plus equals 1, and that's it.
你不需要把所有东西都放在右边
You don't need to put everything on the right-hand side.
这是一个特殊的语法 它说的是完全相同的事情 递增i
This is a special syntax that says the exact same thing, increment i,
但它用的时间更少
but it does it with a few fewer keystrokes.
只是打字更方便 阅读速度更快
It's just a little more pleasant to type, it's a little faster to read,
这只是个会议而已
it's just a convention.
你们当中那些用C C++ Python编程的人--
Those of you who have programmed in C, C++, Python--
不 不是巨蟒
no, not Python.
C、C++、Java、JavaScript可能在前面看到了加号或减号
C, C++, Java, JavaScript might have seen plus-plus before or minus-minus.
对不起 Python没有它 所以您不能使用它
Sorry, Python doesn't have it, so you cannot use that.
这是您的代码行可能获得的最简洁的代码
This is as succinct as your line of code might get.
好的
All right.
让我在这里停下来看看 如果有
Let me pause here to see, then, if there's
关于While循环的这些实现的任何问题
any questions about these implementations of while loops.
观众：我们可以使用像for循环这样的东西吗
AUDIENCE: Can we use stuff like for loops
在开始时将某个i值初始化为
which have a certain i-value initialized to it at the start
它从你放进东西里的特定条件中运行
and it runs from the particular condition you put into the thing
并在你前进的过程中递增？
and increment it as you go along?
大卫·马兰：简而言之 不 你不能做你所描述的事情
DAVID MALAN: Short answer, no, you cannot do what you're describing,
但我们很快就会看到另一种类型的for循环
but there is another type of for loop that we will soon see.
不过 让我们过一会儿再来讨论这个问题
But let's come to that in just a moment.
关于在这里使用循环的其他问题？
Other questions on loops using while here?
观众：所以我对这个流程图有一个问题
AUDIENCE: So I had a question about that flowchart.
大卫·马兰：好的
DAVID MALAN: OK.
观众：有--是的
AUDIENCE: There were-- yeah.
有一些特定的符号代表着特定的陈述--
There were certain symbols for the certain kind of the statements were--
他们是不是真的被用来发表这样的声明--
are they certainly used for that kind of statement that they--
大卫·马兰：是的
DAVID MALAN: They are.
所以我考虑了--
So I deliberate--
我故意使用某些类型的符号 某些形状
I deliberately use certain types of symbols, certain shapes
在这里 椭圆形是启动和停止的常规方式
here whereby an oval is conventional for start and stop.
我将矩形用于任何代码语句 如赋值或打印
I used rectangles for any statement of code, like an assignment or a printing
以此类推
and so forth.
我用钻石来代表你可能会问的问题
And I used diamonds to represent questions that you might ask,
正如我们所看到的情况
conditions as we've seen.
如果你是为了你自己 如果你只是
If you're doing this for yourself, if you're just
试着理解你的代码并把它写下来
trying to make sense of your code and writing it down,
你当然不需要使用这些正式的符号
you certainly don't need to use these formal symbols,
但我试图与一些最佳实践保持一致
but I tried to be consistent with some best practices.
事实上 让我回到同样的画面
And in fact, let me come back to the same picture,
因为这是我们照片的第一个版本
because this was the first version of our picture,
但自那以后 我们已经修改了几次代码
but we've since modified our code a couple of times.
回想一下 这就是我们提出问题的版本
This, recall, was the version where the question we were asking
我是不是不等于0 现在让我继续更改这个代码
was i not equal to 0, let me go ahead and just change this code now
来代表我们做的下一个版本 回想一下
to represent the next version we did, which, recall,
改变了我们的逻辑 从1开始计数
changed our logic to start counting from 1,
它将我们的问题改为检查 因为I小于或等于3
it changed our question to check as i less than or equal to 3,
但是其他的一切都是一样的 除了计数
but then everything else was the same except for the counting, which
现在是正数而不是负数
is now plus instead of minus.
然后我们把它进一步细化 从0数到
And then we refined it a little bit further by counting now from 0 up to
但不是穿过3点
but not through 3.
我们在这里通过将1递增来收紧代码
And we tightened up this code here by just incrementing 1
通过使用稍微更简洁的语法
by using the slightly more succinct syntax.
因此 在这一点上 这些流程图可能会变得越来越没有用处
So at this point, these flowcharts might become less and less useful
对于我们来说 因为一旦你的思想围绕着这个概念
for us, because once you've wrapped your mind around the concept
希望这张照片能帮助我们把这个概念变成现实
and hopefully the picture helps bring that concept to life,
完全专注于代码当然是很好的
it certainly fine to focus entirely on the code
只想着甚至画出这样的东西
and only think about or even draw something like this
如果你需要考虑一些更复杂的事情
if you need to wrap your mind around something more complicated
比你习惯的要多
than you're used to.
好吧 如果可以的话 让我继续说下去 并提出建议
Well, let me go ahead, if I may, and propose
我们使用另一种循环类型转换到另一种方法
that we transition to another approach of types of loops using another
关键字 即for循环
keyword here, namely a for loop.
这个词确实存在于其他语言中
And this is a word that does exist in other languages,
但不一定具有其他语言可能具有的功能
but doesn't necessarily have as many features as other languages might
用它来
use it for.
但是还有一种不同类型的循环--不是While循环 而是for循环
But there is a different type of loop-- not a while loop, but a for loop.
而for循环将允许我们以不同的方式表达自己
And a for loop is going to allow us to express ourselves a little differently,
但要做到这一点 我建议最简单的方法
but to do so, I propose that the easiest way
如果我们在Python语言中引入另一个概念 那就是列表
is if we introduce one other idea in Python, which is that of a list.
在这里 也没有双关语的意思 我们添加到数据类型列表中
And here, too, no pun intended, we're adding to the list of data types
Python所支持的
that Python supports.
我们见过STR或字符串
We've seen strs or strings.
整型或整型
Ints or integers.
浮点值或浮点值
Floats or floating point values.
布尔或布尔表达式
Bools or Boolean expressions.
Python也有列表 这是另一种数据类型
Python also has lists, which is another type of data,
但奇妙的是 这一次可能非常熟悉
but wonderfully, this one is probably pretty familiar.
现实世界中的事物列表就是用Python编写的事物列表
A list of things in the real world is a list of things in Python.
这是一种在同一位置包含多个值的方式
It's a way of containing multiple values all in the same place, all
在同一个变量中
in the same variable.
那么我这么说是什么意思呢？
So what do I mean by this?
让我建议我们回到我们的VS代码
Well let me propose that we go back to our VS Code here,
让我在这里重新开始我的代码 根本不使用While循环
and let me start fresh with my code here and not use a while loop at all,
但让我用这个新的关键字
but let me use this new keyword for.
For循环的工作方式是 它允许您迭代项目列表
The way for loop works is that it allows you to iterate over a list of items.
那么这看起来像什么呢？
So what does this look like?
它可能看起来像这样--
It might look like this--
对于i和以下项目列表 0 1 2
for i and the following list of items, 0, 1, 2.
这是我的起点 在每次迭代中
This is my starting point, and on each iteration
这个循环--也就是说 在每次执行这个循环时
of this loop-- that is, on each execution of this loop again and again,
我想把猫咪打印出来
I want to print out meow.
现在我承认 我已经有点喜欢这段代码的外观了
Now I'll admit, I kind of like the look of this code already
尽管这里有一些新的语法
even though there's some new syntax here,
因为它只是比While循环短
because it's just shorter than the while loop.
While循环刚才有多行
The while loop had multiple lines a moment ago
我是什么 完全由我自己决定
and it was entirely up to me to decide what i is.
我必须检查一个条件 我必须递增或递减i
I have to check a condition, I have to increment or decrement i.
就像我做了很多工作 相对而言
Like I was doing a lot of work, relatively speaking,
让那玩意儿转起来 让那个循环走下去
to make that thing turn, to make that loop going to go.
从某种意义上说 这是非常机械的
It was very mechanical in a sense.
你可以在你的脑海中看到齿轮转动 就像所有这些变量一样
You can in your mind's eye maybe see the gears turning as all of these variables
正在发生变化 这些问题正在被提出
are changing and these questions are being asked.
For循环简化了所有这一切 它只是
A for loop simplifies all of that, and it just
也就是说 如果你想要一个像i这样的变量 一个数字
says, if you want a variable like i, a number,
你事先就知道这个循环要执行多少次--三次
and you know in advance how many times want this loop to execute-- three
我们只会具体说明它是什么
times, we'll just kind of specify what it
就是你想让我显式地接受AS值
is you want i to take on as values explicitly.
在这个循环中 我将被Python自动初始化为0
In this loop, i will be automatically initialized by Python to be 0,
然后猫咪就会被打印出来
then meow will be printed.
然后 Python会自动将i更新为等于1 然后将打印meow
Then Python would automatically update i to equal 1, then meow will be printed.
然后 Python会自动将i更新为2 并打印meow
Then Python will automatically update i to be 2 and meow will be printed.
因为该列表中的值就是这样 所以Python将停止
And because that's it for the values in that list, Python will stop
而且它总共只会叫三次
and it will only meow a total of three times.
名单是什么？
What is the list?
这个程序中的列表正好是 0 逗号 1 逗号 2
The list in this program is exactly that, 0, comma, 1, comma, 2,
注意方括号
and notice the square brackets.
这些不是圆括号 那些是代表列表的方括号
Those aren't parentheses, those are square brackets that represent a list.
作为程序员 这就是可视化的方式--这就是Python所熟知的语言
That's how visually as the programmer-- that's how Python knows as the language
你打算把它列成一个名单
that you intend for that to be a list.
因此 让我继续运行cat.py的这个Python 它的工作方式是一样的
So let me go ahead and run this Python of cat.py, and it works just the same.
但只有两行字
But it's only two lines.
一旦您熟悉了该结构 它就非常容易阅读
It's pretty readable once you have familiarity with that construct,
但就我一贯的观点来说 正确性并不一定
but to my constant point about correctness not necessarily
与设计一样 这个程序在什么意义上可能是
being the same as design, in what sense is this program perhaps
设计得很差？
poorly designed?
它似乎起作用了
It seems to work.
它叫了三次 但为什么这次不能
It meows three times, but why might this not
是解决这个问题的最好办法吗？
be the best way to solve this problem?
即使你以前从未编程过 再一次
Even if you've never programmed before, again,
想想角落里的情况 可能会发生也可能不会发生的事情
think about corner cases, things that may or may not happen.
想一想真正测试代码质量的极端情况
Think about extreme cases that really test the quality of this code.
观众：好的
AUDIENCE: OK.
我想这是因为我们说了0 1 2 3次
I think that because we are saying 0, 1, 2 3 times.
如果你想拿一百万 你可以说1 2 3
And then if you want to take a million, you say 1, 2, 3.
大卫·马兰：是的 确实如此
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
这就是我思考极端情况时的意思
And that's what I mean about thinking about the extreme cases.
如果您试图自己决定您自己的代码是否好
If you're trying to decide for yourself if your own code is good
或者其他人的代码很好 乍一看可能是这样的
or someone else's code is good, it might look so at first glance,
但想一想极端的情况
but think about the extreme.
如果这不是三件事 而是一百万件事呢？
Well, what if it's not three things, it's a million things?
我是说 你真的要把0写到一百万还是0
I mean, are you really going to write out 0 through a million or 0
至9--
through 9--
999,999？
999,999?
就像不 你不会在屏幕上写那么多数字
Like no, you're not going to write that many numbers on the screen
一定有更好的办法
there's got to be a better way.
所以让我们从一开始就做更好的事情
So let's do the better way from the get-go
而不是为做一些糟糕的事情铺平道路
rather than set the stage for doing something poorly.
我们可以解决这个问题来改进设计的一个方法
And the one way we can solve this problem to improve the design
不仅仅是手动指定值列表 使用函数
is don't just manually specify the list of values, use a function,
其他人的随附于Python的函数
someone else's function that comes with Python
这就给了你想要的名单
that gives you the list you want.
而在Python中实现这一点的最简单方法是
And the easiest way to do that in Python is
若要使用名为Range的函数 该函数将返回某个范围的值
to use a function called range that returns to a range of values.
它需要至少一个参数作为输入
It expects as input at least one argument,
这个数字将是您想要取回的值的数量
and that number is going to be the number of values you want back.
这些值将从0开始 一直到1、2 以此类推
Those values are going to start at 0 and go to 1, to 2, and so forth,
但他们将增加两个 但不是通过您指定的数字
but they will go up two but not through the number you specify.
因此 通过指定范围3 您基本上是
So by specifying range 3, you're essentially
返还1、2、3个值
being handed back 1, 2, 3 values.
默认情况下 这些值是0、1和2 仅此而已
And by default, those values are 0, 1, and 2, and that's it.
但这件事的精彩之处在于 霍普认为 如果我这样做
But what's brilliant about this is that now, to Hope's point, if I do
想要叫一百万次--
want to meow a million times--
我的意思是 那是一只愤怒的猫 我现在只需输入一百万就可以做一百万
I mean, that is an angry cat, I can now do a million by just typing a million.
我不需要直接输入0 逗号 1 逗号 2 逗号 3 逗号
I don't have to literally type 0, comma, 1, comma, 2, comma, 3, comma,
4 一直到999,999 我只是这样做
4, all the way up to 999,999, I just do this.
因此 从长远来看 这肯定是一种更好的方式
So that's got to be a better way long-term.
所以这确实是我们可以改进的一个方面
So that's indeed one improvement we can indeed
Make Here仍然使用for循环 但现在使用此Range函数
make here still using a for loop, but now using this range function.
我要向你们展示的是另一件毕德式的东西--
And just to show you something else that's Pythonic--
严格来说 这并不是必需的 但通常
this is not strictly necessary, but it's commonly
完成了 我们可以在这里做一些小的改进
done, there's a minor improvement we can make here,
即使我们只猫叫了三次
even if we're just meowing three times.
请注意 即使我定义了一个变量i 我也从来没有使用过它
And notice that even though I'm defining a variable i, I'm not ever using it.
从逻辑上讲 这是必要的 因为据推测
And it's kind of necessary logically, because Python, presumably,
必须用一些东西来计数
has to use something for counting.
它必须知道它在迭代什么
It has to know what it's iterating over.
但在Python语言中有这样一个约定
But there's this convention in Python where
如果您需要一个变量 仅仅因为编程功能需要
if you need a variable, just because the programming feature requires
它需要进行某种计数或自动更新 但你 人类
it to do some kind of counting or automatic updating, but you, the human,
不关心它的价值 这里是一种毕脱式的改进
don't care about its value, a Pythonic improvement here
将该变量命名为单下划线
would be to name that variable a single underscore.
只是因为它不是必需的 它不
Just because it's not required, it doesn't
改变程序的正确性 但它
change the correctness of the program, but it
它会向同事或老师发出信号
signals to yourself later, it signals to colleagues or teachers that
也在看你的代码 是的 它是一个变量
are looking at your code, too, that yes, it's a variable,
但你不在乎它的名字 因为你以后不用它
but you don't care about its name because you're not using it later,
它只是为了使用这个功能 这个循环在这里
it's just necessary in order to use this feature, this loop in this case here.
这只是一个小小的改进或改变
So just a minor improvement or change there.
但要真正让你对Python的可能性感兴趣
But to really gets you intrigued by what's possible in Python,
我们再进一步
let's take this one step further.
所以如果我们真的想成为Python 这个 如果你以前编程过
So if we really want to be Pythonic, this one, if you've programmed before,
会让你大吃一惊
is kind of going to blow your mind, so to speak,
如果我想让猫叫三次 如果我真的这么做了呢？
whereby if I want the cat to meow three times, what if I actually do this?
print open parenthesis quote-unquote meow times 3.
print, open parenthesis, quote-unquote, meow times 3.
你得有点极客才能觉得这很酷 但这确实有点酷
You have to be kind of a geek to think this is cool, but this is kind of cool.
所以你可以直接打印你想要的
So you can literally just print what you want,
乘以你想要的次数
multiply it by the number of times that you want it,
你会得到完全相同的结果
and you will get back exactly that result.
我好像犯了个错误
Now I've kind of made a mistake here.
让我们看看它的作用
So let's see what this does.
对你们中的一些人来说 它并不像这段代码看起来那么漂亮
It's not quite as beautiful as this code might look to you-- to some of you,
对我
to me.
让我运行cat.py的Python 回车
Let me run Python of cat.py, Enter.
好吧 就像是饿猫之类的
OK, it's a really like hungry cat or something.
它叫得很快
It's meowing really fast.
但我能解决这个问题 我敢打赌
But I can fix this, I bet.
现在让我们来思考一下我们讨论过的一些基本组成部分
Let's think about now some of the basic building blocks we've discussed.
问题显然是 从字面上喵 喵
The problem is clearly that literally meow, meow,
喵喵叫重复了三次 但没有我想要的那么漂亮
meow is being repeated three times, but it's not as pretty as I want it.
我希望它是喵 喵 喵在不同的线上
I want it to be meow, meow, meow on separate lines.
有什么可能的解决方案
What might be a possible solution here while still
使用这个乘法运算符？
using this multiplication operator?
回想一下
And think back.
我们已经使用加号连接字符串
We've used plus to concatenate strings.
显然 可以使用乘法连接字符串 但不止一次
You can apparently use multiplication to concatenate strings, but more than once
一遍又一遍
again and again and again.
我怎么才能在不恢复
How could I clean this up without reverting
到我的For循环或我的While循环 并且仍然以这种方式使用乘法？
to my for loop or my while loop and still use multiplication in this way?
观众：我们可以使用转义序列 即反斜杠n
AUDIENCE: We can use the escape sequence which would be backslash n.
大卫·马兰：太棒了
DAVID MALAN: Amazing.
是
Yes.
回想一下反斜杠n 这是您作为程序员的方式
Think back to backslash n, which is the way you as the programmer
可以在代码中表示新行
can express a new line in code.
我想 如果我听从你的建议 我会在里面加一个反斜杠
And I think, if I take your advice, I put a backslash in there inside
所以在每一句M-E-O-W的结尾 都有一行新的
of my quotes, so that at the end of every M-E-O-W, there's a new line,
让我们看看这是什么样子
let's see how this looks.
让我清空屏幕并运行cat.py的Python
Let me clear my screen and run Python of cat.py.
好的 就差那么一点了
OK, so close.
我喜欢这个
I like this.
让我去找别人吧
Let me call on someone else.
我唯一不喜欢的是--我知道我现在真的很挑剔--
The only thing I don't like-- and I know I'm being really nitpicky now--
它是猫叫 猫叫 猫叫在不同的线上
is that it's meow, meow, meow on separate lines,
但有一条额外的空白线 我只是不喜欢审美上的
but there's this extra blank line, which I'm just not loving aesthetically.
观众：我认为我们可以使n等于列--
AUDIENCE: I think we can make n equal to column--
列 而不是--像斜杠n
column, not-- like a slash n.
大卫·马兰：是的
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
所以 这里也一样 就像我们在过去几周看到的所有事情一样
So here, too, like all of these things we've seen in past weeks
就像是走到了一起
are kind of coming together.
回想一下 打印函数允许您控制行尾是什么
Recall that the print function lets you control what the line ending is.
默认情况下 它本身就是反斜杠n
By default, it's backslash n itself.
这就是为什么在这张照片的最后
Which is why at the very end of this print,
光标将再次移动到下一行
the cursor is being moved again to the next line.
我们只需要推翻它就行了
Well, we need to just override that.
让我在这里进入我的代码 并将其更改为逗号n
So let me go into my code here and let me change this to comma n
等于引号-非引号 因此它不再是默认的反斜杠n
equals quote-unquote so that it's no longer the default backslash n,
相反 现在它将什么都不是
it's instead now going to be nothing whatsoever.
那么 希望这应该会消除额外的空行
That should eliminate, then, hopefully that additional blank line.
所以让我在这里运行最后一次 cat.py的Python 回车
So let me run this one last time here, Python of cat.py, Enter,
现在我们就知道了
and there we have it.
所以现在 至少在编程过程中 它是
So now, at least as programming goes, it's
我可以把这些提炼成一小行 这真是太酷了
kind of cool that I can distill this into a short line
一下子表达了自己的想法
and express myself all at once.
现在 公平地说 它的可读性有所降低
Now to be fair, it's a little less readable.
就像现在我有反斜杠n 我有3倍
Like now I've got backslash n, I've got times 3,
我得到了n等于引号-不引号
I've got n equals quote-unquote.
所以你不必用这种方式做事
So you don't have to do things this way.
我之前使用for循环的方法 完全没问题
My previous approach with a for loop, totally fine.
我之前使用While循环的方法 完全可以 在某种意义上
My previous approach with a while loop, totally fine, and in some sense,
完美的设计
perfectly well-designed.
但这只是另一种方式
But this is just yet another way to do it,
但如果你或你的老师 你的同事 你的朋友
but it's not a good thing if you or your teacher, your colleague, your friend
将会很难读懂你自己的代码
are going to struggle to read your own code.
但这是一些语言实际上没有的一个Python特性
But this is a feature of Python that some languages do not, in fact, have.
好吧 让我提议让事情变得更有趣
All right, well let me propose that things get more interesting still
如果我们不只是猫叫三次
if we're not just meowing three times only,
但我们的猫咪叫声次数是可变的
but we're meowing some variable number of times.
让我们来问问用户这只猫应该叫几次
Let's ask the user how many times this cat should meow.
所以让我清理一下屏幕 让我想想 好吧
So let me clear the screen here, and let me figure out, well,
我如何从用户那里获得号码？
how do I get a number from the user?
这里的问题是 如果我想让用户给我一个数字
The catch here is that if I want the user to give me a number,
我不是在做数学 本质上 我在猫叫 因此 用户
I'm not doing math, per se, I'm meowing, and therefore, the user
必须给我一个积极的价值
has to give me a positive value.
用户必须给我一个正值
The user has to give me a positive value.
那么 我怎么能坚持这一点呢？
So how can I insist on this?
如果我这样做 n等于输入的int 那么n是什么 问号？
Well, if I just do this, n equals int of input, what's n, question mark?
嗯 我想确认一下--
Well, I want to check like--
我可以说 如果n小于0-
I could say if n is less than 0--
如果它是阴性的 那么我可以这样做
like if it's negative, well I could do this.
好吧 那就再问一遍
Well, then ask again.
INT INPUT n是什么 问号？
Int, input, what's n, question mark?
好的 那么如果用户仍然不给我一个正数怎么办？
OK, well what if the user still doesn't give me a positive number?
如果真的很难 他们没有注意到呢
What if being really difficult they're not paying attention
然后他们输入了两个负数？
and they typed in two negative numbers?
如果n小于0 那么我们再来一次 N等于--
Well, if n is less than 0, well, let's do it again. n equals--
这不会有好的结局
this does not end well.
你不能无限次地不停地检查 是否定的吗
You can't infinitely many times keep checking, is it negative,
它是负面的 还是负面的？
is it negative, or is it negative?
这个程序永远不会被写完
The program would never be done written.
所以我们可以做这件事 我想更好 也许用一个循环
So we can do this I think better maybe with a loop.
因此 让我提出这一点
So let me propose this.
在Python中有一个非常常见的范例 当您
A very common paradigm in Python, when you
希望获得与您的特定期望相匹配的用户输入
want to get user input that matches a certain expectation you have,
这一切都是积极的 都是消极的 或者只是类似的东西
that it's all positive, that it's all negative, or just something like that,
你马上就会说虽然是真的
you just immediately say while true.
你故意的 有点危险 但很老套
You deliberately, and a little dangerously but a very conventionally,
引发无限循环
induce an infinite loop.
那么什么是无限循环呢？
Now what is an infinite loop?
它只是一个永远不会消失的东西
It's just one that goes forever.
我们已经看到了这种情况是如何在数学上偶然发生的
And we've seen how that can happen accidentally mathematically.
当你说虽然是真的时 这绝对会发生
It's absolutely going to happen when you say while true.
为什么？
Why?
嗯 真正问题的答案总是正确的
Well, the answer to the true question is always true.
因此 这是一种故意诱导循环的方式
So this is a way of deliberately inducing a loop that
默认情况下 它将永远消失
by default is going to go forever.
所以我们需要一种方法来打破这个循环 当
So we're going to need a way of breaking out of this loop when
我们有我们想要的号码
we have the number we want.
大会 虽然在这个会议的其他方面
The convention, though inside of this otherwise
无限循环就是问你关心的问题
an infinite loop is to ask the question you care about,
比如通过提示用户输入来给我一个int
like give me an int by prompting the user for input.
比如n是什么 问号？
Like what's n, question mark?
然后问你自己的问题
And then just ask your question.
因此 如果n小于0 那么我认为我们希望Python继续
So if n is less than 0, then I think we want Python to just continue
以再次提示用户
to prompt the user again.
也就是说 我们希望代码停留在循环中 调用输入函数
That is, we want the code to stay in the loop, recall the input function,
并希望用户给我们一个更好的答案
and hope that the user gives us a better answer.
如果这一次它小于0 那么让我们按字面意思
If this time around it's less than 0, so let's just literally
使用Python的关键字Continue 其意思是
use Python's keyword continue, which says
就是这样--继续保持在这个循环中
just that-- continue to stay within this loop.
否则 如果不小于0 让我们继续前进 只需突破
Else, if it's not less than 0, let's go ahead and just break out
使用了Python语言中的另一个关键字Break
of the loop altogether using another keyword in Python, break.
在这种情况下 Break将使您脱离最近开始的循环
Break will break you out of the most recently begun loop in this case
如果不是n小于0的情况
if it's not the case that n is less than 0.
所以这是可行的 它将允许我们获得一个大于或等于0的值
So this will work, and it will allow us to get a value that 0 or greater
来自用户 但我认为我们可以进一步收紧它 以免
from the user, but I think we can tighten it up further so as to not
不厌其烦地假设 然后 等等
bother having an if, and, and else.
为什么我们不直接说 如果n大于0 继续并中断呢？
Why don't we instead just say, if n is greater than 0, go ahead and break?
事实上 这并不是一个有趣的节目
In fact, it's not that interesting a program
如果我们甚至允许用户输入0
if we even allow the user to type in 0.
所以让我们等到他们给我们一个大于0的整数
So let's wait until they give us an integer that is greater than 0
然后跳出这个循环
and then break out of this loop.
我现在在这里能做些什么呢？
And what can I now do down here?
对于i来说 不管n是什么值 都可以打印猫咪
For i in range of whatever that value n is, print meow.
老实说 我不需要我在这里 所以让我回到那个原则上
And honestly, I don't need i here, so let me come back to that principle
在此之前
before.
让我把它改成下划线
And let me just change it to an underscore
如果你愿意的话 只是想表达一下毕多德式的意思
just to be Pythonic, if you will.
那到底是怎么回事？
So what's going on?
第1行到第4行故意实现无限循环
Lines 1 through 4 deliberately implement an infinite loop
否则 默认情况下 这种情况将永远消失
that otherwise by default is going to go forever.
但我在问一个问题 在那个循环里
But I'm asking a question, inside of that loop,
在第2行上从用户那里获得一个int之后 我将检查
after getting an int from the user on line 2, I'm then checking,
它是否大于0？
is it greater than 0?
还是说是0？
Or is it 0?
是阴性的吗？
Is it negative?
对于猫咪来说 这一切都说不通
None of which makes sense for meowing cat.
好像我想让那只猫至少叫一次
Like I want the cat to meow at least one time.
因此 如果它大于0 则中断
So if it is greater than 0, break.
这个Break语句 即使它是缩进的 缩进了两次
And this break statement, even though it's indented, indented twice,
具有中断最近开始的While循环的效果
has the effect of breaking out of the most recently begun while loop.
因此 一旦用户给你一个正值
So once the user gives you a positive value,
然后我们到了第6行 在这一点上我们猫叫了很多次 因为
then we get to line 6, at which point we meow that many times because
6号线和7号线
of line 6 and 7.
所以 如果我现在运行这个cat.py的Python 输入 那么 n是什么？
So if I run this now Python of cat.py, Enter, well, what's n?
让我们从我们开始的3开始 喵
Let's start with 3 where we began, meow, meow, meow.
这一次 让我继续并增加我的终端窗口的大小
Well this time, let me go ahead and increase the size of my terminal window
只是暂时的
just temporarily.
让我运行Cat.py的Python 让我运行10次 现在猫咪10次
Let me run Python of cat.py, let me do it 10 times, meow 10 times now
出现在屏幕上
appears on the screen.
这里要说的不仅仅是我们可以猫叫10次
And the takeaways here are not just that we can meow 10 times
或者一次又一次地做某事 但这
or do something again and again, but this
是在您想要再次做某事时 在Python中非常常见的范例
is a very common paradigm in Python when you want to do something again
一次又一次 但只有在用户真正给你
and again and again, but only until the user actually gives you
这是你在这里所关心的价值
a value that you care about here.
现在让我向你求婚 因为我们练习了
And let me propose actually now that we practice
更多的是我们一直在宣扬的 特别是当涉及到 比如说--
a little more what we've been preaching, especially when it comes to, say--
尤其是当涉及到编写您自己的函数时
especially when it comes to say writing your own functions.
现在我都在猫叫了 可能会
Now that I'm doing all this meowing, it might
很高兴能真正拥有一个Monow函数 它是Python的发明者
be nice to actually have a meow function that the inventors of Python
没想到 所以就让我来做吧
didn't envision, so let me do this.
让我实际删除所有这些代码 让我继续执行此操作
Let me actually get rid of all this code and let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续说明定义一个主函数 就像我以前做过的那样
Let me go ahead and say define a main function, as I've done before,
让我盲目地叫猫咪3
and let me just blindly call meow 3.
猫咪还不存在 但当它存在的时候 那就太好了
Meow doesn't exist yet, but when it does, that'll be great.
所以 现在让我来定义一下猫咪
So let me go ahead now and define meow.
所以我是猫咪函数应该接受的输入
So am I meow function should take as input
一个名为n的参数 或者我想要的任何东西 这部分现在很容易了
a parameter called n or anything I want, and this part's pretty easy now.
你是怎么叫n次的？
How do you meow n times?
好的 为了给n加下划线 也就是n的范围 你可以直接打印猫咪
Well, for underscore n, the range of n, go ahead and just print meow.
所以和以前一样的代码 这里没有什么新鲜事
So same code as before, nothing new here,
我只是把这个逻辑放在一个猫咪函数中
I'm just putting that logic inside of a meow function
这将会产生打印猫咪的副作用
that's going to have this side effect of printing meow.
现在 像以前一样 让我到下面来 让我确保我调用Main
And now, as before, let me go down here and let me make sure I call main.
如果我现在运行这段代码 猫的巨蟒 喵
And if I now run this code, Python of cat.py, meow, meow, meow.
它总是会做3 因为我已经硬编码到3
It's always going to do three because I've hardcoded to 3.
好吧 让我们在这里做一个改进
Well, let's make one improvement here.
现在让我继续下去 也许可以这样做
Let me go ahead now and maybe do this.
让我向用户索要一个号码
Let me ask the user for a number.
让我们这样说 数字等于得到数字
So let's say something like this, number equals get number.
好的
All right.
遗憾的是 在Python中没有函数
Unfortunately, there is no function in Python
从用户那里获得正数的被调用的GET号码
called get number that gets a positive number from the user,
但这是我可以发明的
but I can invent that.
所以定义Get Number 打开Paren 关闭Paren
So define get number, open paren, close paren.
然后在这个函数内部 让我这样做
And then inside of this function, let me do this.
如果为真 则继续并从用户那里获取一个数字
While true, go ahead and get a number from the user,
将其转换为整型 问他们 n是什么 问号？
converting it to an int asking them, what's n, question mark?
如果n是我想要的 它就是一个大于0的值
And then if n is what I want, it's a greater than 0 value,
一个正数 我不一定要打破这一次
a positive number, I don't want to break this time necessarily,
虽然我可以
although I could.
相反 我希望返回值 这样我就可以实际执行此操作
I instead want to return the value so I can actually do this instead.
而这也是Python的一个特性
And this, too, is a feature of Python.
这种能力不仅仅是从一块代码中解脱出来
This ability not to just break out of a block of code,
还可以在代码中返回值
but also to return a value in code.
实际上 返回一个值使您最终能够
To actually return a value gives you the ability, ultimately,
显式返回值 以便您的函数不只有一个边
to return explicitly a value so that your function has not just a side
效果是必然的 但它实际上是回馈 就像输入一样
effect, necessarily, but it actually hands back, just like input does,
就像int做的一样 就像Float做的一样 对用户来说是一个实际值
just like int does, just like float does, an actual value to the user.
现在澄清一下 我不需要在这里返回n
Now to be clear, I don't have to return n here.
我仍然可以像过去对代码所做的那样跳出循环
I can still break out of the loop as I've done in the past with code
像这样 但在循环之后 我仍然必须返回
like this, but then after the loop, I still have to return.
所以这里发生的事情是 如果你使用Break来跳出循环
And so what's happening here is that if you use break to get out of the loop,
但您需要从函数中传回一个值
but you need to hand back a value from a function,
现在您仍然必须使用RETURN关键字
you still have to use the return keyword now
显式地要么像我一样在循环中 要么现在在循环之外
explicitly either in the loop as I did or now outside of the loop
但仍在函数内部
but still inside of the function.
我现在要做的最后一件事是改变
The last thing I'm going to do here now is change
我们之前硬编码的那个3 实际上
that 3, which we hardcoded earlier, to actually
是我们从用户那里获得的变量的值
be the value of the variable we've gotten from the user
所以现在在这里 如果我运行cat.py的Python 输入 n是什么？
so that now down here, if I run Python of cat.py, Enter, what's n?
我可以输入3 我可以得到我的三声 或者如果我只想要一声
I can type in 3, I get my three meows, or if I only want one,
我现在得到了一只猫叫
I now get one meow instead.
好的
All right.
因此 如果我们现在有能力在这些循环中一次又一次地做事情
So if we now have this ability to do things again and again in these loops,
让我们看看我们是否不能解决其他一些问题 通过
let's see if we can't solve some other problems via which
周期性地表达自己 但也会得到一些有趣的答案
to express ourselves cyclically, but get back some interesting answers as well.
例如 让我提议 我们看起来
And let me propose, for instance, that we look
更密切地关注这些榜单
a little more closely at these lists.
事实证明 在Python中 而且实际上 在一般的程序中
It turns out that in Python, and really, in programs in general,
有一个值列表很有用 因为我们是
it's useful to have a list of values, because we're
将能够处理越来越多的数据、越来越大的数据集
going to be able to work with more and more data, larger and larger data sets.
因此 让我建议我们回到VS代码这里
So let me propose that we come back to VS Code here
让我们来做一些可能对一些人来说有点熟悉的事情
and let's do something that's perhaps a little familiar to some folks,
霍格沃茨的世界
the world of Hogwarts.
让我继续编写一个名为霍格沃茨的文件
And let me go ahead and code up a file called Hogwarts,
让我们看看我们能不能列出霍格沃茨的学生名单
and let's see if we can't have a list of students at Hogwarts here.
因此 我有一个名为hogwarts.py的新选项卡
So I have a new tab called hogwarts.py.
让我继续下去 提议我在这个程序中定义
and let me go ahead and propose that I just define in this program
一份我事先知道名字的学生名单
a list of students whose names I know in advance.
因此 我暂时不会让用户输入
So I'm not going to get user input for now.
我从一开始就知道这三个人
I'm just going to know from the get-go that the three
我想考虑的学生是这些
students I want to consider are these.
我们的变量将被称为学生
Our variable is going to be called students.
就像我在过去做的那样 它等于一个方括号 它
It's going to equal, as I've done in the past, a square bracket, which
意思是 嘿 这是一份清单
means, hey, here comes a list.
这些值将是引号中的赫敏 因为它是
And those values are going to be Hermione in quotes, because it's
一个字符串；用引号引起来的哈里 因为它是一个字符串；然后罗恩用引号
a string; Harry in quotes, because it's a string; and then Ron in quotes,
因为它也是一根线
because it's a string as well.
这是一个长度为3的列表
So this is a list of length 3.
它在精神上类似于我之前列出的长度为3的列表
It's similar in spirit to my list of length 3 earlier,
但这有3个整数 0 1 2
but that had 3 ints, 0, 1, 2.
现在 我有了一个包含三个字符串的列表
Now I have a list of three strings instead.
而这在目前并不是很有用
And this isn't very useful at the moment,
但让我做点事作为我自己的支票
but let me just do something as a check for myself.
让我把这些学生逐一打印出来
Let me print out each of these students.
嗯 等一下 我怎么打印列表的内容呢？
Well wait a minute, how do I print the contents of a list?
在过去 当我们打印变量时
Well, in the past, when we've printed a variable,
我们刚刚打印出了变量的名称
we've just printed out the name of the variable.
但我不想一下子把赫敏、哈利和罗恩都打印出来
But I don't want to print out all of Hermione and Harry and Ron all at once.
也许我想先打印出赫敏 然后是哈利 然后是罗恩
Maybe I want to print out Hermione first, then Harry, then Ron.
所以我需要一种更准确的方式来表达
So I need a way to express more precisely which
我想要此列表中的值吗？
value do I want from this list?
在Python中实现这一点的方法是以另一种方式使用方括号
And the way you do this in Python is you use square brackets in another way.
如果你有一个变量--在这个例子中 叫做学生
If you have a variable-- in this case, called students,
你想要进入这个变量并获得一个特定值--
and you want to go inside of that variable and get a specific value--
也就是说 您想要索引到列表中
that is to say, you want to index into the list,
您可以这样使用方括号 在方括号中使用数字
you use square brackets this way using numbers inside of the square brackets.
这就是我们看到用0来思考和计算的有用之处
And here's where we see that it is useful to think and count in terms of 0
上行而不是1上行
on up instead of 1 on up.
Python中的这些列表是零索引的
These lists in Python are, shall we say, zero-indexed.
列表中的第一项位于位置0 Python列表中的第二项位于位置0
The first item in a list is at location 0, the second item in a Python list
第一个是位置1 第三个是位置2
is that location 1, and the third is that location 2.
所以你在精神上总是差一点 但你会习惯的
So you're always kind of off by one mentally, but you get used to it,
如果你从来没有编程过 随着时间的推移
if you've never programmed before, over time.
让我把这三个学生都打印出来
So let me print out all three students.
让我打印出学生括号0 然后学生括号1
So let me print out students bracket 0, then students bracket 1.
最后 让我打印学生括号2
Then lastly, let me print students bracket 2,
这是第三句也是最后一句
and this is my third and final line.
当然 如果我运行这段代码 它可能会做你猜的事情
And of course, if I run this code, it probably does what you would guess.
如果我运行hogwarts.py的Python 有赫敏、哈利和罗恩
If I run Python of hogwarts.py, there's Hermione, Harry, and Ron
每个人都有自己的路线
each on their own lines there.
但肯定有更好的办法尤其是
But there's got to be a better way, especially
如果我事先不知道谁会出现在这个名单上
if I don't know in advance who's going to be in this list,
如果明年霍格沃茨有新学生
if next year there's some new students at Hogwarts,
我们可以用循环来自动地做一些事情
we can use a loop to do something automatically
而不必手动输入0 然后输入1和2
without having to manually type out 0 and then 1 and 2.
这是Python的另一个特性
Well, here's another feature of Python.
你可以使用for循环不仅仅是从0到1再到2
You can use a for loop not just to count from 0 to 1 to 2,
你可以用Python来覆盖任何东西
you can use Python to just iterate over anything.
不仅仅是数字 还有字符串
Not just numbers, but strings.
所以我真的可以这么做
So I could actually do this.
对于学生中的学生 冒号 然后在下面缩进
For student in students, colon, and then indented underneath that,
我可以说印刷学生
I can say print student.
不管我有三个学生 四个还是四百个
Now it doesn't matter if I have 3 students or 4 or 400,
这两行代码 这个循环会为我打印所有这些学生
these two lines of code, this loop will print all of those students for me
一次一个
one at a time.
所以如果我现在运行hogwarts.py的Python 有相同的列表
So if I now run Python of hogwarts.py, there's the same list,
但我不需要提前知道名单有多长
but I don't need to know in advance how long that actual list is.
注意 我做了一个有意识的决定
Now notice, I made a conscious decision here.
我没有把这个变量叫做下划线 因为这次我
I didn't call this variable underscore, because this time I'm
使用变量
using the variable.
虽然我能做到这一点 现在 不
And while I could do this, now, no, no, no, no,
你的代码太晦涩了
your code is getting way too cryptic.
如果你给变量命名为下划线
If you're naming the variable underscore and you're
使用变量underscore 现在你帮不了任何人
using the variable underscore, now you're helping no one.
现在你把读者搞糊涂了 你自己也搞糊涂了
Now you're confusing the reader, yourself down the line,
您应该按变量的原样来命名它们
you should call your variables what they are.
所以这是一个非常合适的名字 虽然我相信你可以想出其他名字
So a very appropriate name, though I'm sure you could come up with others,
会是学生 而在这里 你可以说你也会继续当学生
would be student, and here, you could say you would stay student as well.
如果你想说得更简洁些 那就是
If you'd prefer to be more succinct, it's
在这样的循环中做一些简洁的事情并不是不合理的
not unreasonable to do something succinct in a loop like this.
对于S来说 在学生名单中 使用的字母可能与
For s in students, using maybe the same letter that the list
它本身就是这样开始的 但再说一次 为什么要费心呢？
itself begins with, but again, why bother?
Python应该更具可读性
Python is meant to be more readable.
如果您有学生列表 请一次迭代一个学生
If you have a list of students, iterate over them one student at a time.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看现在是否有关于名单的问题
Let me pause here to see if there's now questions about lists
正如我现在定义的那样 在本例中是字符串列表
as I've now defined them, a list of strings in this case,
或者现在使用for循环迭代并打印每个名称
or using a for loop now to iterate over and print each of those names.
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
那么 在这种情况下 没有必要启动学生吗？
So is it not necessary to initiate student in this case?
或者我们可以只在循环中声明一个变量？
Or we can just declare a variable in the loop?
大卫·马兰：问得好
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
您无需手动对其进行初始化
You do not need to manually initialize it.
Python负责将Student变量初始化为Hermione
Python takes care of initializing the student variable to Hermione
第一 然后是哈利 然后是罗恩 第三
first, then Harry second, then Ron third.
与其他语言不同 您不需要自己将其初始化为某个东西
Unlike other languages, you don't need to initialize it to something yourself,
它只是存在 而且会奏效的
it just exists and it will work.
其他关于循环和列表的问题是这样的吗？
Other questions on loops and lists in this way?
观众：既然你描述了Break 那么有没有
AUDIENCE: Since you describe break, so is there
有没有继续的概念 这样我们就可以在循环中跳过特定的情况？
any concept of continuing so that we can skip a particular case in loops?
大卫·马兰：是的
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
您也可以继续使用其他语法
You can continue using another syntax as well.
我们还没有证明这一点
We haven't shown that.
目前 我们只关注休息时间
For now we focused only on break.
观众：好的
AUDIENCE: OK.
那么这个for循环可以与哈希表或其他类型的循环一起工作吗
So can this for loop work with either hash tables or different kind
是表还是数组？
of tables or arrays?
大卫·马兰：确实如此
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
所以我们在这一点上超前了
So we're getting ahead of ourselves there,
但在Python中还有其他类型的数据
but there are yet other types of data in Python,
实际上 您也可以使用for循环来迭代这些代码
and indeed, you can use a for loop to iterate over those as well.
可以说 任何可迭代的东西都是
Anything that is iterable, so to speak, is
可以与这样的循环一起使用的数据片段
a piece of data that can be used with a loop like this.
但更多关于这些的--很快就会有更多的关于这些的
But more on those-- more on those soon.
事实上 让我过渡到这里来展示另一种解决方案
In fact, let me transition here to show just another way of solving
同样的问题 因为到目前为止 当我们使用循环时
this same problem, because up until now when we've used loops,
我们真的依赖于数字 这很好
we really have relied on numbers, and that's fine
如果你更喜欢呆在那个地方的话
if you prefer to stay in that space.
假设我确实想使用像I和0这样的数字进行迭代
Suppose I did want to iterate using numbers like i and 0,
1、2等等
1, 2, and so forth.
让我建议我们可以按如下方式更改此代码
Let me propose that we could change this code as follows.
如果您更愿意考虑 或者如果您正在进行的项目
If you would prefer to think about, or if the program you're
尝试实施需要使用这样的数字
trying to implement requires that you use numbers like this,
你可能会这么做
you might do this.
对于我来说--嗯 我不想只说学生
For i in-- well, I don't want to just say students,
因为那样我就不再是一个数字了
because then i is not going to be a number.
我将成为赫敏 然后是哈利 然后是罗恩
i is going to be literally Hermione, then Harry, then Ron.
我需要从0到1再到2迭代
I need to iterate from 0 to 1 to 2.
如果具有三个元素的列表具有这些位置 0 1 2
If I a list with three elements has these locations, 0, 1, 2,
我需要以某种方式创建一个从0开始到2结束的循环
I need to create a loop somehow that starts at 0 and ends at 2.
以前 当我想这么做的时候 我需要射程
Previously when I wanted to do that, I needed range,
但这两项计划行不通
but this 2 is not going to work.
我不能只说在学生的范围内
I can't just say in the range of students,
因为学生不是数字 也不是整数
because students is not a number, it's not an integer,
所以你不能把球传给射程
so you can't pass it to range.
Range需要一个整数
Range expects an integer.
但这里有一个解决方案
But there is a solution here.
原来在Python语言中有一个名为LENGTH或LEN的函数 L-E-N
It turns out that there is a function in Python called length or len, L-E-N,
这会告诉你清单的长度 以及以后的其他事情
that will tell you the length of a list and other things down the line, too.
现在我想我可以组装这些积木 并以一种方式
And now I think I can assemble these building blocks and a way that can
请允许我以这种方式使用数字
allow me to use numbers in this way.
所以Range不需要字符串列表 它需要一个数字
So range doesn't take a list of strings, it takes a number,
理想情况下 这个数字应该是3
and ideally, that number is going to be 3,
所以我得到了一个值的范围 0、1和2
so I get a range of values, 0, 1, and 2.
所以我想我可以像这样嵌套我的函数
So I think I can nest my functions like this.
如果我首先得到学生名单的长度 那将是3
If I first get the length of the students list, that's going to be 3,
然后 我将返回值作为参数传递
then I pass that return value as the argument
对于Range 这将返回一个值的范围 0 然后1 然后是2
to range, that's going to give me back a range of values, 0, then 1, then 2.
如果我想的话 这将允许我用代码来做什么
And what that's going to allow me to do then in code if I want
不仅仅是这样
is not just this.
我现在可以打印出来了 学生们 这是现在
I could do print now students bracket i, and this is now
我们看到的语法正在变得非常有表现力--新的 也许
where the syntax we're seeing is getting very expressive-- new and perhaps
不熟悉
unfamiliar.
但如果我能做左方括号 0 左方括号 或左方括号
But if I can do open bracket, 0, close bracket, or open bracket, 1,
左方括号 或左方括号 2 右方括号 结果是
close bracket, or open bracket, 2, close bracket, turns out,
我实际上可以在里面放一个变量 然后我
I can actually put a variable in there and I
可以表示括号内的任何数字
can express any number inside of those brackets
以便在循环中动态地打印出所有这些
so as to print these all out dynamically in a loop.
让我来做这件事 巨蟒of hogwarts.py 回车
Let me do this, Python of hogwarts.py, Enter,
这是赫敏、哈里和罗恩
there's Hermione, Harry, and Ron.
现在 如果我只是好奇 我只想戳
And now if I'm just curious, I just want to poke
或许我想做个排名 比如谁
around or maybe I want to do a ranking, like who
排名前三的学生是在学校还是在格兰芬多？
are the top three students in the school or in Gryffindor?
嗯 我们已经看到 我可以一次打印多个东西
Well, I can print multiple things at a time, we've seen.
让我打印出来的不仅仅是现场的学生
Let me print out not just the students at location
而是让我们先打印I 然后打印位置I的学生
i, but rather, let's print i first and then the student at location i.
所以要打印两件事 我们知道打印可以有两个论点
So two things to print, and we know that print can take two arguments,
我们以前见过 它们会被一个空格隔开
we've seen that before, they'll be separated by a space.
让我继续并重新运行这个
Let me go ahead and rerun this.
现在我明白了 好吧 赫敏是最好的学生 但她是第零名
Now I see that, OK, Hermione is the top student, but she's in zeroth place.
这有点奇怪
That's a little weird.
就像我们不需要向使用我的程序的人展示
Like we don't need to show the human using my program
我们从0开始数
that we started counting at 0.
我可以把这里清理干净
I can clean this up.
我可以在这里的i上加1 现在我们
I can just add 1 to the i up here, and now we
查看排名前三的学生名单
see a top three list of students.
赫敏是第一名 哈利是第二名 当然 罗恩是第三名
Hermione is number 1, Harry's number 2, and of course, Ron is number 3.
因此 我们也可以访问所有这些相同的值
So we can get access to all of those same values as well.
这些清单上现在还有什么问题吗？
Are there any questions now on these lists?
这些清单上现在有什么问题吗？
Any questions now on these lists?
这个长度 这个范围 还是其他？
This length, these ranges, or otherwise?
观众：我的问题是 对于我在射程内 你能再解释一次吗？
AUDIENCE: My question is, for i in range, can you explain this once more?
大卫·马兰：当然
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
所以 让我及时回顾一下
So let me rewind in time.
我们一开始就这么做
We started off doing this.
I in 0 1 2 然后我们用这种方式打印三次
For i in 0, 1, 2, and then we print it out meow three times in that way.
For循环的工作方式是它创建
The way that for loop works is that it creates
一个变量 我把它叫做i 但我想叫它什么都行
for you a variable that I've called i, but I could call it anything I want.
然后 它将i初始赋值给列表中的第一个项
It then assigns i initially to the first thing in the list.
然后 它会自动将i赋给列表中的下一项
It then automatically assigns i to the next thing in the list.
然后它将i赋给列表中的第三个项目
And then it assigns i to the third thing in the list.
每次它都会执行下面的所有缩进代码
And each time it does all of the indented code underneath.
然而 我们意识到 这是不可能的
We realize, though, that this is not going
如果我想做一百万次这样的事情 要有很好的伸缩性
to scale well if I want to do something like a million times.
因此 我们引入了Range
So we introduced range instead.
这产生了做同样事情的效果
That has the effect of doing the same thing.
它给我返回了一系列的值--实际上是三件事的清单
It returns to me a range of values-- a list of three things, really,
所以行为是完全一样的
so the behavior is exactly the same.
如果我们现在快进到霍格沃茨的例子 我正在做的是
If we now fast forward to this Hogwarts example now, though, what I'm doing
就是把这些小点子结合起来
is just combining these smaller ideas.
我仍在创建一个for循环
I'm still creating a for loop.
我还在创建一个名为i的变量
I'm still creating a variable called i.
我想通过一系列的值来做这件事 但是有多少值呢？
I want to do it over a range of values, but how many values?
如果我使用LENGTH函数并传递给LENGTH函数
Well, if I use the length function and pass to the length function
价值清单 长度的人生目标
the list of values, length's purpose in life
就是告诉我这张单子有多长 是3张
is to tell me how long is this list, and it's 3.
所以这几乎就像以前 我刚刚做了这样的事情
So that's almost as though before, I had just done something like this,
但我不想硬编码3 我想动态地计算出
but I don't want to hardcode 3, I want to dynamically figure out
霍格沃茨有多少学生
how many students are at Hogwarts.
所以我只是作曲
So I'm just composing, composing, composing,
或者嵌套所有这些不同的想法
or nesting all of these various ideas.
好的 如果可以的话 现在让我过渡到--
All right, if I may, let me transition now to--
在霍格沃茨仍然引入了之前的最后一种数据类型
in Hogwarts still to introduce one final type of data before
我们把所有的东西和几个最终的节目结合在一起
we combine everything with a few final programs.
事实证明 在Python中 不仅仅是字符串 而不仅仅是
It turns out in Python, there's not just strings, not just
整数 而不仅仅是浮点值 而不是
ints, not just floating point values, not
只是无稽之谈 不只是列表 还有
just bools, not just lists there are also
所谓的词典或词典是一种数据结构 它允许您
what are called dictionaries or dics, are a data structure that allows you
将一个值与另一个值相关联
to associate one value with another.
字面意思是一本像人类世界一样的词典
Literally a dictionary like in the human world.
如果你打开一本词典 无论是英语还是其他人类语言
If you were to open a dictionary, be it in English or any other human language,
词典里有什么？
what's inside of a dictionary?
嗯 它是一堆单词和定义
Well, it's a bunch of words and definitions.
不过 他是一名计算机科学家和一名程序员
A computer scientist, though, and a programmer
会更笼统地将这些描述为键和值
would describe those more generically as keys and values, something
与其他事物联系在一起
associated with something else.
词典就是这么回事
That's all a dictionary is.
它允许你将某物与另一物联系在一起
It allows you to associate something with something else.
注意 这已经比列表更强大、更有趣了
And notice, this is already more powerful, more interesting than a list.
列表只是由多个值组成的集合
A list is just a set of multiple values.
但如果你愿意的话 字典是二维的
But a dictionary is two-dimensional, if you will.
就像一本人类词典 一本书 它让人联想到一些东西
Just like a human dictionary, a book, it associates something
用一些其他的东西 比如单词和它们的定义
with something else like words with their definitions.
那么 这实际上意味着什么呢？
Now what does this actually mean in practice?
假设我们想要跟踪
Well suppose that we wanted to keep track
谁在霍格沃茨的哪栋房子里
of who is in what house at Hogwarts.
嗯 我可以单用清单就能做到
Well, I could do it using lists alone.
让我回到这里的VS代码 让我
Let me go back to VS Code here and let me
只是暂时的--但我最终不会喜欢的--
just temporarily-- but in a way that I'm not going to like ultimately--
让我创建另一个名为house的变量
let me create another variable called houses,
把它设为格兰芬多 相当于赫敏的房子
set it equal to Gryffindor, corresponding to Hermione's house,
格兰芬多 对应于哈利的房子 格兰芬多
Gryffindor, corresponding to Harry's house, and Gryffindor,
与罗恩的房子相对应
corresponding to Ron's house.
让我们把德拉科也加进去
And let's add Draco in there.
所以我们现在有四个学生而不是三个
So we now have four instead of three students
只是为了让我们有一点变化 他在斯莱特林
just so we have a little variety, and he was in Slytherin.
所以现在我们有两个名单
So now we have two lists.
我们可以在我们之间达成一致
And we could just agree amongst ourselves
谁是第一名 谁就改变了人生
that whoever is first in the students variable lives
在房子的第一个价值中
in the first value in houses.
学生中排名第二的人住在第二所房子里
Whoever is second in students lives in the second house.
学生中排名第三的人住在第三栋房子里
Who's ever third in students lives in the third house.
我们可以这么做
We could do that.
但老实说 这将很快瓦解
But honestly, that is going to break down quickly
当我们有很多学生时 当我们有很多房子时
when we have a lot of students, when we have a lot of houses,
如果我们想要跟踪更多的东西呢？
and what if we want to keep track of more things than that?
如果我们想要跟踪每个学生的家呢
What if we want to keep track of every student's house
而守护神 这个他们魔术般的形象呢？
and the patronus, this image that they conjure up magically?
那么 我们需要第三份清单 就像--这只是
Well, then we need a third list like-- this is just
如果我们只是在荣誉系统上 很快就会变得一团糟
going to get messy quickly if we're just on the honor system
使用多个列表 其中所有内容都在逻辑上排成一行
using multiple lists where everything lines up logically.
当您的代码变得更复杂时 结果不会很好
It doesn't end up well when your code gets more complicated.
但我确实想要实施这个想法
But I do want to implement this idea.
我想把某事与某事联系起来
I want to associate something with something.
有房子的学生 有房子的学生 有房子的学生
A student with a house, a student with a house, a student with a house
以此类推 那么我该如何着手做这些呢？
and so forth, so how can I go about doing this?
好的 让我回到我的代码 让
Well, let me go back to my code here and let
我建议我们使用一本Python词典来完成这项工作
me propose that we do this using a Python dictionary.
这是我们将要看到的最后一种新语法
And this is the last of the new syntax, really, that we'll see .
下面是新的语法
Here's the new syntax.
我们不使用方括号 而是
Instead of using square brackets, we're going
在词典中也使用花括号
to use curly braces for dictionaries as well.
我们已经在f字符串的上下文中看到了完全无关的花括号
We've seen curly braces in the context of f strings completely unrelated.
有时你会用完键盘上的键和语言的作者
Sometimes you run out of keys on the keyboard and the authors of a language
需要开始以不同的方式重新使用符号 这是
need to start reusing symbols in different ways, that's
即将发生的事情
what's about to happen.
我们正在以不同的方式使用花括号
We're using curly braces in a different way.
现在 让我创建一个名为Students的变量
Now so let me create a variable called students.
让我继续并将其设置为等于打开
And let me go ahead and set it equal to open
花括号和闭合花括号
curly brace and closed curly brace.
这本词典目前是一本空词典
This is an empty dictionary at the moment.
以下是词典的工作原理
And here's how a dictionary works.
它允许你将一些东西与其他东西联系在一起
It allows you to associate something with something else,
然后你像这样做
and you do that like this.
赫敏 引号-不引号 冒号 然后是它的值
Hermione, quote-unquote, colon, and then the value thereof.
你想把赫敏和什么联系在一起？
What do you want to associate with Hermione?
嗯 格兰芬多
Well, Gryffindor.
我想把哈利和什么联系在一起？
What do I want to associate Harry with?
我想把他和格兰芬多联系起来
Well, I want to associate him with Gryffindor.
我想把罗恩和什么联系在一起？
What do I want to associate Ron with?
我想把他和格兰芬多联系起来
Well, I want to associate him with Gryffindor.
嗯 这实际上不会--这会很快变得非常丑陋
Well, this is actually not going to-- this is going to get very ugly quickly.
一旦我们加上德拉科和斯莱特林 我的代码就会变得太长
Once we add in Draco and Slytherin, my code is going to get too long,
它要开始包装了
it's going to start wrapping.
所以这纯粹是审美上的
So this is purely aesthetic.
它在Python和其他语言中是完全可以接受的
It is perfectly acceptable in Python and other languages
为了更容易地格式化代码 只需添加新行
to format your code a little more readily and just add new lines
如果它让它更具可读性的话
if it makes it more readable.
而这样做的一种方法可能如下所示
And one way of doing this might be as follows.
我的花托还在这 我的花托还在下面
I still have my curly brace up here, I still have my curly brace down here,
但请注意 它现在的可读性更好了
but notice, it's a little more readable now
因为我的钥匙在左边 我的东西 我的价值观
in that I have my keys on the left, my somethings, and my values
在右边 是我的其他东西
on the right, my other somethings.
只是从上到下略读起来更容易一些
It's just a little easier to skim top to bottom.
您也可以设置不同的格式
You could format it differently as well.
但我现在要说的是 德拉科
But I'm going to go ahead and add in now Draco
当然 他住在斯莱特林
who lives, of course, in Slytherin.
现在我把每一把钥匙都放在左边
So now I have each of these keys on the left
和右边的价值观 这真的 再一次
and values on the right, which is really, again,
这只是这个想法的一个代码实现 一个小图表
just a code implementation of this idea, a little chart
你可以用纸铅笔写出来
that you might write up with paper pencil
当把某物与另一物联系在一起时
when associating something with something else.
那么 我现在如何以一种有趣的方式使用这段代码呢？
So how do I now use this code in an interesting way?
语法几乎是相同的
The syntax is almost the same.
如果我想打印出第一个学生 赫敏的家
If I want to print out the very first student, Hermione's house,
我能做到的
I could do this.
打印出变量的名称 但我需要进入变量内部
Print out the name of the variable, but I need to go inside of the variable.
我需要把它编入索引
I need to index into it.
字典的巧妙之处在于 尽管列表
And what's neat about dictionaries is that whereas lists
有数字形式的地点--
have locations that are numeric--
0 1 2；赫敏 哈利 罗恩
0, 1, 2; Hermione, Harry, Ron respectively,
可以说 词典允许你使用实际的单词作为你的索引
dictionaries allow you to use actual words as your indices, so to speak,
您的索引以深入了解它们
your indexes to get inside of them.
所以如果你想打印出赫敏的房子
So if you want to print out Hermione's house,
你关心的关键是 引用-引用 赫敏
the key you care about is, quote-unquote, Hermione,
这里的语法要做的是--注意 它不是数字0、1或2
and what this syntax here will do-- notice, it's not a number 0 or 1 or 2.
这真的是赫敏的名字
It's literally Hermione's name.
这就像早先去看图表 然后说 好吧 把赫敏给我
This is like going to the chart earlier and saying, all right, give me Hermione
是我的钥匙 格兰芬多是价值
is my key, Gryffindor is the value.
这就是我们在这里从语法上所做的
That's what we're doing here syntactically.
我们正在寻找赫敏 并得到它的价值
We're looking up Hermione and getting the value thereof.
所以 如果我回到我的代码 它应该会打印出格兰芬多
So if I go back to my code, that should print out Gryffindor.
如果我这样做几次 学生们 括号 引号-引号
And if I do this a few times, students, bracket, quote-unquote,
哈利应该把哈利的房子给我
Harry should give me Harry's house.
打印学生 打开括号 罗恩 这应该会给我罗恩的房子
Print students, open bracket, Ron, that should give me Ron's house.
最后 如果我对学生们这样做 Branket Draco
And then lastly, if I do this with students, bracket, Draco,
这应该会给我德拉科的房子
that should give me Draco's house.
现在它仍然是一个小手册 我打赌我们可以改进这个
Now it's a little manual still, and I bet we can improve this,
但是让我在hogwarts.py上运行Python 我们
but let me run Python on hogwarts.py and we
应该去看看格兰芬多 斯莱特林
should see Gryffindor, Gryffindor, Gryffindor, Slytherin, which
这正是我们所期待的
is exactly what we'd expect.
现在我们所做的一切 再一次 是我们刚刚搬到
Now all we've done, again, is we've just now moved
从只有一个简单的名字列表到再一次 两个维度
from having just a simple list of names to, again, two dimensions,
像我们在纸上那样联想--用铅笔写东西和东西
associating like we would on paper-pencil something with something
否则 分别为带有值的键
else, keys with values respectively.
如果你愿意 请允许我 尽管我知道这有点花哨
Allow me, if you will, even though I realize this is getting a little fancy,
请允许我在这里稍微升级一下 并从查看
allow me to escalate things slightly here and transition from looking
例如 在那里的模式中 只是对这些值进行硬编码
at just, for instance, that pattern there, just a hard coding those values
实际上 要更动态地打印这些内容
there to actually printing these out more dynamically.
让我继续使用我们的循环 这个问题也出现在前面
Let me go ahead and use our loop, and this question came up earlier as well,
让我继续说 对于学生中的每个学生
let me go ahead and say for each student in students,
继续打印出来 例如 学生们在--
go ahead and print out, for instance, the students variable at--
好吧 让我们先说学生优先
well, let's just say student first.
让我们简单点吧
Let's keep it simple.
所以这还不会那么有趣
So this is not going to be that interesting yet,
但是 当我运行hogwarts.py的Python并按Enter时 请注意 我应该看到什么？
but when I run Python of hogwarts.py and hit Enter, notice, what should I see?
让我在这里回答一个问题 看看我是什么
Let me take a question here to see what am I
当我在为学生做学生会的时候 我现在按回车键的时候会看到吗？
going to see when I hit Enter now when I'm doing for student in students?
观众：是的 我想我们只会看到钥匙
AUDIENCE: Yeah, I think we will only see keys.
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
这么好的直觉
So good intuition.
它可能是双向的
It could have gone both ways.
可能是价值问题 房子问题
Could have been values, the houses.
但是 当您在Python中使用for循环迭代字典时
But when you use a for loop in Python to iterate over a dictionary, by design,
它遍历所有键
it iterates over all of the keys.
所以我们应该看看 我想 赫敏、哈利、罗恩和德拉科
So we should see, I think, Hermione, Harry, Ron, and Draco.
现在让我按Enter键 Enter键 确实 你说的完全正确
Let me hit Enter now, Enter, and indeed, you're exactly right,
我们只看到了钥匙
we see just the keys.
但如果我真正关心的是
But that's not really that useful if what I really care about
是谁住在哪里 我能把两个都打印出来吗？
is who lives where, can I print out both?
嗯 我想我可以
Well, I think I can.
让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我打印出的不仅仅是学生的名字 钥匙
Let me print out not just the student's name, the key,
但让我使用关键字 他们的名字 来索引词典
but let me use the key, their name, to index into the dictionary.
如果我在词典里知道这个词 让我查一下它的释义
If I know the word in the dictionary, let me look up its definition.
如果我知道那个学生的名字 让我查一下他们的房子
If I know the student's name, let me look up their house,
而这个的语法 就像一个列表一样 是学生 括号
and the syntax for this, just like a list, is students, bracket.
就像过去我们在我还是数字的时候用i一样
And just like in the past we used i when i was a number,
我们也可以在词典中使用字符串
we can also with a dictionary use a string.
所以如果学生的名字是关键 那么这个语法 学生
So if the student's name is the key, then this syntax, students,
开括号 学生 关闭括号将前往赫敏的位置
open bracket, student, close bracket will go to Hermione's location
然后拿回她的房子
and get back her house.
会去哈利的住处 拿回他的房子 等等
Will go to Harry's location and get back his house and so forth.
因此 如果我执行hogwarts.py的Python 输入 现在我
So if I do Python of hogwarts.py, Enter, now I
见赫敏 格兰芬多；哈利 格兰芬多；罗恩 格兰芬多；
see Hermione, Gryffindor; Harry, Gryffindor; Ron, Gryffindor;
还有德拉科·斯莱特林
and Draco Slytherin.
现在看起来我给了他们所有人新的姓氏
Now it looks like I've given them all new last names,
但我可以把它清理干净
but I can clean that up.
这只是一个打印的东西
This is just a print thing.
让我们继续更改默认空格中的分隔符
Let's go ahead and change our separator from the default space
可能是一个空格 逗号
to maybe a space, comma.
现在使用打印功能 让我再次运行相同的程序 输入
And just using print features now, let me run the same program again, Enter,
现在我只需要在里面加几个漂亮的逗号来说明
now I've just got some nice pretty commas in there to make clear
赫敏的姓氏其实不是格兰芬多
that Hermione's last name is not, in fact, Gryffindor,
但这只是一个指纹细节
but that's just a print detail.
那么 对这些词典还有什么问题吗？还有我刚才做了什么？
Any questions, then, on these dictionaries and what I've just done?
关于这些词典的问题 然后在这里循环？
Questions on these dictionaries and this looping over then here?
观众：我就是想不通学生中的学生
AUDIENCE: I just can't get my head around the for student in students.
如果我--如果我是对的就纠正我
If I'm-- just correct me if I'm right.
这是否意味着它导入了学生名单并使用了索引--
Does that mean it imports the list of students and uses the indexes--
或者换句话说 赫敏、哈利和罗恩作为实际中的索引--
or in other words, Hermione, Harry, and Ron as the indexes in the actual--
学生名单？
the list of students?
大卫·马兰：正确
DAVID MALAN: Correct.
因此 这只是Python的一个功能
So this is just a feature of Python.
当您在字典中使用for循环时 会发生这样的情况
When you use a for loop with a dictionary, what happens is this.
如果这是字典 关键字在上面 值在下面
If this is the dictionary here with the keys on top and the values on bottom,
您可以选择变量的名称
you get to choose what the variable is called.
我给我的变量学生打电话 只是因为这有道理
I called my variable student just because it makes sense,
因为我每次只想要一个学生
because I want one student at a time.
For循环所做的 就像它以前对数字所做的那样
And what for loop does, just like it did with numbers before,
0、1和2 它允许我 例如
the 0, the 1, and the 2, it allows me to, for instance,
将学生初始设置为与赫梅林的名字相等
set student equal initially to Hermelin's name.
然后循环的下一个迭代 下一个周期
And then the next iteration of the loop, the next cycle,
将学生设置为哈利的名字 然后是罗恩 然后是德拉科
sets student equal to Harry's name, then Ron, then Draco.
这是自然而然发生的
It just happens automatically.
这就是Python解释器在以下情况下为您做的事情
Like that is what the Python interpreter does for you when
它看到了这样的for循环
it sees a for loop like that.
因此 它在本质上非常类似于在列表上使用for循环迭代
So it's very similar in spirit to iterating with a for loop over a list,
而不是迭代该数字位置
but rather than iterate over the numeric location,
0 1 2 它遍历此表示形式中的粗体键
0, 1, 2, it iterates over the bold-faced keys in this representation here
图形化的
graphically.
请允许我再给我们举一个关于霍格沃茨的例子
And allow me to give us one other example on Hogwarts
在我们看另一个熟悉的领域之前
before we look at one other familiar domain.
冒着事态升级的风险
At the risk of things escalating a little bit,
让我提议让我们用最后一位霍格沃茨来继续这个故事
let me propose that we continue the story with one final Hogwarts
像这样的例子
example like this.
如果我们有更多关于我们每个学生的信息会怎么样？
What if we have more information about each of our students?
这是不可避免的
And this is inevitable.
如果您正在实施一个与人或客户建立数据库的计划
If you're implementing a program that's a database with people or customers,
或员工或其他任何东西 你可以想象
or employees or anything else, you can imagine
拥有关于您在程序中表示的任何内容的大量数据
having a lot of data about anything you're representing in your program
这里
here.
为了便于讨论 假设霍格沃茨的每个学生 当然
For the sake of discussion, suppose that every student at Hogwarts, of course,
有了名字 他们已经有了房子 但他们也有了守护神
has a name, they have already a house, but they also have a patronus.
对于那些不熟悉的人来说 这是动物或实体
For those unfamiliar, this is the animal or entity
当他们施展某种魔法咒语时 魔杖的末端就会发出这种魔力
that comes out of the end of their wand when they make a certain magical spell.
这里的重点是 我们想要将
The point here being is that we want to associate not
对学生只有一件事 但有多件事
just one thing with the student, but multiple things
还有--他们的名字 他们的房子 以及他们的赞助人
as well-- their name, their house, and their patronus in this case.
那么 这样的代码可能是什么样子的呢？
Well, what might code like this look like?
好了 让我回到hogwarts.py 让我重新开始一小会儿
Well, let me go back to hogwarts.py and let me start fresh for just a moment.
让我建议我用更多的数据来加强这一点
And let me propose that I enhance this with a bit more data.
这些数据将如下所示
And this data is going to look as follows.
我的学生现在变了 我建议我们把它当作一个列表
My students variable now, I'm going to propose we think of it as a list.
如果我们有一份如下的词典清单 会怎么样？
What if we have a list of dictionaries as follows?
事实上 我想在这里真正实现这一图景
Indeed I want to literally implement this picture here.
所以请注意 我之前的图片只代表了一本词典
So notice that my previous picture just represented a single dictionary.
但假设我想编写一份词典列表
But suppose I wanted to compose a list of dictionaries.
也就是说 对于学生来说--所以有四名学生
That is, for students-- so a list of four students.
假设这些学生本身就是一本词典
And suppose that each of those students is itself a dictionary,
键值对、键和值的集合
a collection of key value pairs, keys and values,
一件又一件
something and something else.
好的 这是我们可以用代码实现的另一种方法
Well, here's one other way we can do this in code.
让我回到这里的VS代码 并定义一个名为
Let me go back to VS Code here and let me define a variable called
等同于列表的学生
students that is equal to a list.
我会先发制人地将光标移动到不同的行上
And I'm going to preemptively move my cursor onto separate lines,
因为我知道这会很漫长 而且我
because I know this is going to be long, and I
我想将此列表中的所有元素都放入其中
want to fit all of the elements of this list inside of it.
我现在要创建一本词典 每个学生一本词典
I'm now going to create a dictionary, one dictionary per student.
我如何创建一本词典？
And how do I create a dictionary?
我只是用那些花括号
I just use those curly braces.
但这取决于我来定义那些关键是什么
But it's up to me to define what those keys are.
让我提出这一次的一个关键
And let me propose that one key this time
不会明确是学生的名字 是吗？
won't be the student's name explicitly, it
字面上是单词名字 在那里 将有名字赫敏
will literally be the word name, and there, going to have the name Hermione.
同一个学生将有另一把名为House的钥匙
The same student is going to have another key called house
价值将是格兰芬多
and the value is going to be Gryffindor.
而同一个学生将拥有第三把钥匙 名为Patronus
And the same student is going to have a third key called patronus,
而它的价值将是--
and the value of that is going to be--
我不得不去查一查--根据书上的说法 是一只水獭
I had to look it up-- an otter, according to the book.
现在 我将在该列表中创建第二个词典
Now I'm going to create a second dictionary inside of this list.
再说一次 词典就像字面意思
And again, a dictionary is like literally
就像人类的词典一样
like the human dictionary of words.
这是一本包含关键和价值观、词汇和定义的书
It's a book that contains keys and values, words and definitions.
我在每本词典里储存的三个单词是什么？
What are the three words I'm storing in each of my dictionaries?
名字 房子和守护神
Name, house, and patronus.
这些词对赫敏的定义是什么？
What are the definitions of those words for Hermione?
分别是赫敏、格兰芬多和水獭
Hermione, Gryffindor, and otter respectively.
对哈里来说 这本新词典的释义将有所不同
For Harry, the definitions are going to be different in this new dictionary.
让我再给自己配一副花箍
Let me give myself another pair of curly braces
然后说这个 名字 引号 冒号 哈利
and say this, name, quote-unquote, colon, Harry.
这里的房子又一次将是格兰芬多
House here is, again, going to be Gryffindor.
而我认识的这位 他的守护神 在这种情况下 将是一只雄鹿
And this one I knew, his patronus, is going to be, in this case, a stag.
接下来是第三本词典
Next, a third dictionary.
这里的名字将是罗恩
The name here will be Ron.
我会像这样继续做下去
And I'm going to go ahead and do that just like this.
接下来 我得到了房子 他也是格兰芬多
Next, I have the house, and he, too, was Gryffindor.
最后 我要查一查 罗恩的赞助人是一只杰克·罗素梗犬
Lastly, had to look this one up, Ron's patronus was a Jack Russell terrier.
最后是德拉科
Lastly is Draco.
在第四本词典中--又一对花括号
In a fourth dictionary now-- so another pair of curly braces,
当然 这名学生的名字是德拉科
the name of the student is, of course, Draco.
这个学生的房子是斯莱特林
The house of this student is Slytherin.
而德拉科 有趣的是 至少根据互联网上的说法
And Draco, interestingly enough, at least according to the internet,
没有守护神
has no patronus.
从未在书中或电影中出现过
Was never revealed in the books or the movies.
事实证明 这实际上是一个很棒的可教的时刻
So it turns out, this is actually a wonderful teachable moment.
在Python中有一个特殊的关键字 字面意思是None N-O-N-E
There is a special key word in Python that is literally None, and N-O-N-E,
第一个字母大写
with the first letter capitalized.
这正式地代表了价值的缺失
This represents officially the absence of a value.
所以我可以草率地做一些类似引用-引用的事情
So I could a little sloppily do something like quote-unquote,
但这是否意味着我没有抽出时间来打字呢？
but does that mean I didn't get around to typing it or not?
从语义上说 字面上没有 一个特殊的关键字 这是有点清楚的
It's a little clear semantically to say literally None, a special keyword
我知道德拉科没有守护神
in Python to make clear that I know Draco has no patronus,
这不仅仅是我的疏忽
it's not just an oversight on my part.
现在我有了这个 我在电脑内存里有什么？
Now that I have this, what do I have in the computer's memory?
我有一个名单
I have a list.
我怎么知道这是名单
How do I know it's a list?
因为我在开头看到一个方括号
Because I see a square bracket at the beginning and another square bracket
到最后
at the end.
这只是我的视觉线索 好吧 我不一定知道
That's just my visual clue, OK, I don't know necessarily
这里还有什么 但有一张清单
what else is going on here, but there's a list of something.
名单上有什么？
What is in that list?
在这里 语法也是我们的线索
Well, here, too, the syntax is our clue.
因为第2行以花括号开始并以花括号结束
Because this line 2 starts with a curly brace and ends with a curly brace,
我只知道 那是一个字典 一个键值对的集合
I just know, that is a dictionary, a collection of key value pairs.
现在这些都完美地显示在我的屏幕上 所以我
Now this all fit on my screen perfectly, so I
并没有麻烦将所有的键值对移动到新的行上
didn't bother moving all of the key value pairs onto new lines,
它会变得很高 所以这次我把它放在一起
it would have made it really tall, so I kept it all together here this time.
但是这第一本字典有多少个键呢？
But how many keys does this first dictionary have?
换句话说 在赫敏的物理字典里
Put another way, in Hermione's physical dictionary,
那本字典里有多少单词？
how many words are in that dictionary?
三.
Three.
这些词是名字 房子和守护神
The words are name, house, and patronus.
这些词的三个定义或价值是什么
What are the three definitions or values of those words
在赫敏的字典里
in Hermione's dictionary?
赫敏 格兰芬多 水獭
Hermione, Gryffindor, and otter respectively.
同样的故事也发生在哈利身上 然后是罗恩
And the same story goes for Harry, then for Ron,
那么对于德拉科我特意选择了
then for Draco, I have, by design, chosen
给他们字典 所有相同的键 所有相同的名字
to give them dictionaries that have all the same keys, all the same names,
但它们都有独特的价值
but they all have unique values.
这就是我的设计 这是我作为一个程序员的特权
And that's my design, that's my prerogative as a programmer.
那么 为什么这在今天结束时有用呢？
So why is this useful at the end of the day now?
我有一整套有趣的数据
I have access to a whole collection of interesting data about all
我仍然可以做循环
of these students, and I can still do a loop.
我可以说 对于学生中的学生来说
I can say for students in students, that's
允许我浏览一下学生名单
going to allow me to iterate over this list of students.
让我一次只打印一件东西
And let me go ahead and print out just one thing at a time.
我把现在学生的名字打印出来
Let me print out the current student's name.
尽管字典很复杂 但这应该很方便
So as complicated as the dictionary is, this should be pretty comfortable.
对于学生中的学生 只需迭代列表中的每个学生
For student in students is just going to iterate over every student in the list.
总计1 2 3 4
1, 2, 3, 4 total.
下一行将打印NAME键的值
The next line is just going to print out the value of the name key.
这就像打开物理词典 查找单词名称
It's like opening a physical dictionary, looking up the word name,
给我们赫敏、哈利、罗恩和德拉科
and giving us Hermione, Harry, Ron, and Draco
分别来自每个词典
respectively from each dictionary.
因此 如果我运行这个版本的霍格沃茨 然后按Enter键 在那里 我会得到所有三个
So if I run this version of Hogwarts and hit Enter, there, I get all three
他们的名字
of their names.
但如果我想要更多的信息呢？
But what if I want more information than that?
我要他们的名字和他们的房子
I want both their names and their houses.
好的 只要加上普莱特的论点 学生 左括号 房子
Well, just add to print's arguments student, open bracket, house,
右方括号
close bracket.
好的 让我们继续运行这个
All right, let's go ahead and run this.
Python of hogwarts.py并按Enter
Python of hogwarts.py and hit Enter.
所以我现在看到了赫敏 格兰芬多 哈利 格兰芬多 等等
So I now see Hermione, Gryffindor; Harry, Gryffindor; and so forth.
好的 我们可以在美学上把这件事清理一下
Well, we can aesthetically clean this up a little
通过添加带有印刷体的分隔符 如逗号和空格
bit by adding a separator with print, like a comma and a space,
这样 当我再次运行此程序时 我现在
just so that when I run this again, I now
请看用逗号分隔这些值
see some comma separating these values.
但请记住 学生不仅有一个名字 也不仅仅是
But recall that students have not just a name, not just
一栋房子 还有那个守护神
a house, but also that patronus.
因此 如果我们也想打印出来 我们现在
So if we want to print out that, too, we now
我有为每个学生编写同一本词典所使用的语法
have the syntax via which to go into that same dictionary for each student
并以他们的名义输出他们的赞助人和他们的房子
and output their patronus as well as their house in their name.
所以如果我最后一次运行这个程序 现在我
So if I run this program one final time, now I
请参阅本词典中的所有数据
see all of the data in this here dictionary.
因此 我相信 一下子要消化的东西很多
So this is a lot to absorb all at once, I'm sure.
这是我们最后一种新的数据类型
It's the last of our new data types.
在清单的顶端 我们有这些词典
On top of lists, we have these dictionaries,
但同样 一本词典 在一天结束的时候
but again, a dictionary, at the end of the day,
只是类似于这些值的值的集合
is just a collection of values similar to these values
在这里 您可以将键与值相关联
here that allow you to associate keys with values.
这个程序的第一个版本从字面上看与学生的
And the first version of this program associated literally the student's
名字和他们的房子 但后来我意识到
names with their houses, but then I realized
在我的下一个版本中 等等 如果每个学生都没有
in my next version, wait a minute, what if every student has not
只是房子里的一个名字 但是一个守护神？
just a name in a house, but a patronus?
让我们真正标准化密钥的名称
Let's actually standardize the names of our keys
是名字、房子和守护神 然后是这些关键字的价值
to be name, house, and patronus, and then the values of those keys
实际上可以是数据 比如赫敏、格兰芬多、水獭等等
can actually be the data, like Hermione, Gryffindor, otter, and so forth.
现在关于这些词典及其迭代的问题是什么？
Questions now on these dictionaries and iteration thereof?
听众：我只是在想 假设这本词典很大
AUDIENCE: I just was wondering, suppose the dictionary is very huge,
如果我想找一个特定的学生
and if I want to look up for a specific student,
那么我怎么知道从哪里看那个学生呢？
so how do I know where to look that student from?
比如我们能按字母顺序排序吗？
Like can we sort it out in alphabetical order
或数字顺序或类似的东西？
or numeric order or anything like that?
大卫·马兰：简而言之 是的
DAVID MALAN: In short answer, yes.
Python的特点之一是它使这些词典非常高
One of the features of Python is that it makes these dictionaries very highly
为你表演的
performant for you.
也就是说 即使它们非常大 因为它们将在未来几周内
That is, even if they're very large, as they will be in future weeks
当我们操作更多的数据时 Python会找到这些数据
when we manipulate more data, Python will find the data
你很快就会关心你的
you care about quickly for you.
事实上 这是语言的一个特点
And in fact, that is a feature of the language,
这是一本词典的一个特点 可以让你快速获得数据
that is a feature of a dictionary to get you the data quickly.
还有一些你可以使用的函数
And there are functions that you can use.
你可以对数据进行分类 你可以筛选它
You can sort the data, you can sift through it,
你可以像我们最终所做的那样 做非常出色的手术
you can do very performant operations as we eventually will.
那么 请允许我提议 当我们结束这些循环时
Allow me, then, to propose, as we wrap up these loops,
我们只解决了最后几个问题 可能会
that we solve just a few final problems that will perhaps
至少唤起了对往年的美好回忆
evoke fond memories of yesteryear, at least
对我来说 在我成长过程中最喜欢的游戏之一
for me, wherein one of my favorite games growing up
这张是在最初的任天堂上的吗？
was this one here on the original Nintendo.
这是一个角色向上移动的二维世界
And this is a two-dimensional world where the characters move up,
向下 向右 不是太靠左 跳过
down, and right, not so much to the left, in jumping over
像这样的金字塔和障碍物
pyramids and obstructions like these.
请允许我提议我们用这个来启发灵感
And allow me to propose that we use this just for inspiration,
不是做像这样色彩鲜艳或图形化的事情 而是
not to do something that's quite as colorful or graphical as this, but just
例如 要关注世界中部的这一障碍
to focus on, for instance, this barrier in the middle of the world
在这里 马里奥或路易吉不得不跳过
here that Mario or Luigi had to jump over.
所以这里看起来就像是三块砖一块一块地踩在一起
And so this here seems to be like three bricks stepped on top of one another.
我们不会把事情做得很生动
And we won't do things quite graphically,
但让我们只实现一个非常简单的基于Python的文本版本
but let's just implement a very simple Python-based version of this textually
可能只使用散列来制作砖块
using maybe just hashes for bricks.
因为这里有一个模式 一个在另一个之上 而我
Because there's a pattern here, one on top of the other, and I
我打赌我们可以用很多方法来解决这个问题
bet we can solve this in any number of ways.
好了 让我在这里切换回VS代码
Well, let me switch back over to VS Code here
让我建议我们使用代码创建一个名为mario.py的程序
and let me propose that we create a program called mario.py using code
在终端窗口中
in the terminal window.
然后在这里 让我从实现相同的图景开始
And then up here, let me start by implementing that same picture
尽可能简单地打印出散列
as simply as I can, printing out just literally the hash,
然后是散列 然后是第三个最终散列
and then the hash, and then a third final hash.
这将是一个非常文本的近似值
This is going to be a very textual approximation of it,
但我认为 如果我运行Python mario.py 我已经
but I think if I run Python mario.py, I've
可以说 我得到了一个非常简单的相同的砖柱版本
got a very simple version of that same column of bricks, so to speak.
但你可以想象在一场比赛中
But you can imagine that certainly in a game
可能这些柱子会变高或变低
where maybe these columns get higher or lower,
如果能写出更多的代码就好了
it would be nice to write code that's actually a little more
而不是仅仅使用打印 这就是字面意思
dynamic than that and doesn't just use print, print, print, which is literally
复制和粘贴 似乎是这样的
copy and paste, it would seem.
所以至少让我采纳今天的一些经验教训
So let me at least adopt some of today's lessons
学到了东西 然后做了这样的事情
learned and instead do something like this.
为了在3的范围内加下划线 现在让我们一次只打印其中的一个
For underscore in range of 3, let's now print out just one of these at a time.
但事实是 我现在用3来标示
But the fact that I've now used a 3 to range
意思是如果我想把它改成更大或更小的
means if I want to change it to something bigger or smaller,
我在一个地方改变它 而不是在三个或更多的地方
I change it in one place not in three or more places.
当然 这个代码也是如此 如果我没有弄错的话
And this code, too, of course, if I got it right,
会打印出一模一样的东西
is just going to print out the exact same thing.
所以我们在这里迭代
So we're iterating here.
但让我们看看我们现在能不能把我们的讨论
But let's see if we can't now integrate our discussion
编写我们自己的函数 以开始编写一些更具动感的东西
of writing functions of our own to begin writing something a little more dynamic
并最终解决更复杂的问题
and solving more complicated problems ultimately.
函数的优点之一是
One of the nice things about functions is
它们不仅允许我们编写我们可以使用和重复使用的代码
that they allow us to not just write code that we can use and reuse,
它们允许我们创建抽象 如果您愿意的话
they allow us to create abstractions, if you will.
抽象是对可能更复杂的概念的简化
An abstraction is a simplification of a potentially more complicated idea.
在几周的时间里 我们已经看到了几次这样的情况
And we've seen this a few times over the course of the weeks.
例如 我们有一个名为Hello的函数 当然 它不能
For instance, we had a function called hello, which, granted, didn't do
所有这些 它只是打印了问候
all that much, it just printed hello.
但它让我可以准确地理解它的功能
But it allowed me to think about the function as exactly what it does,
不是一般的打印东西 而是字面上的问候
not generically printing something, but literally saying hello.
我已经能够使用类似的方法获得一个数字 方法是定义
I've been able to get a number using something similar by defining
我自己的函数 比如Get Number
my own function like get number.
好吧 让我继续 举个例子 暂时假设
Well let me go ahead and, for instance, assume for the moment
在我的主要功能中 我已经有了先见之明
that I've had the forethought to, in my function main,
使用名为Print Column的函数
use a function called print column.
这似乎是一个使用一个函数的好名字
That seems as good a name as any to use a function that
打印一列砖
prints a column of bricks.
那么 我现在该如何着手实施
Well, how can I go about now implementing
这种抽象 这种简单的打印列与实际代码的想法？
this abstraction, this simple idea of print column with actual code?
嗯 我们以前见过def 我们可以做到这一点
Well, we've seen before with def, we can do just that.
让我定义一个名为Print Column函数
Let me define a function called print column.
一般来说 让我接受一个名为Height的参数作为它的输入
Let me accept as its input, generically speaking, a parameter called height.
我可以称它为n或h 但现在用身高表示会更清楚一些
I could call it n or h, but it would be a little more explicit now with height
只是为了提醒我自己它在做什么
just so I remind myself what it's doing.
现在我想我可以借用以前的一些相同的代码
And now I think I can just borrow some of that same code from before.
对于n个高度范围的下划线 请继续并打印出单个散列
For underscore n range of height, go ahead and print out a single hash.
然后在整个程序结束时 让我们只调用main
And then at the end of this whole program, let's just call main.
所以我把代码变得有点复杂了
So I've kind of complicated the code.
它目前还不能做更多的事情 但它
It doesn't do anything more just yet, but it's
让我来解决我认为将要发生的事情
setting me up for solving what I think are going
更复杂的问题
to be more sophisticated problems.
如果我运行Python of mario.py 我们又回到了开始的地方
If I run Python of mario.py, we're back where we began.
但我现在有了一个函数 一个抽象 打印专栏
But I now have a function, an abstraction, print column,
这会让我考虑打印
that's going to allow me to think about printing
一次是马里奥世界的一小部分
some chunk of the world of Mario at a time.
我也可以用不同的方式做到这一点
And I can do this in different ways, too.
请注意 如果我真的想 我可以做这样的事情
Notice that if I really want, I could do something like this.
我可以用不同方式实现现在打印列
I could implement now print column in different ways,
尤其是当我在代码中使用打印列时
especially if I am using print column all over my code,
或者 我的一位同事 一位朋友 互联网上的其他人
or maybe still, a colleague of mine, a friend, someone else on the internet
正在使用我的打印栏功能
is using my print column function.
您编写的函数还有什么好的地方
What's also nice about functions you've written
是您可以更改它们的底层实现细节
is you can change the underlying implementation details of them,
但只要您不更改函数的名称或其参数
but so long as you don't change the name of the function or its parameters
或者它的回报是什么 如果说有什么不同的话 那就是没有人知道其中的区别
or what it returns, if anything no one else knows the difference.
您可以更改内部实现
You can change the internal implementation
如果你想改进它或随着时间的推移进行修复 你想要多少就有多少
as much as you want if you want to improve it or make fixes over time.
例如 我们可以实现打印列的另一种方式
So for instance, another way we could implement print column,
回想一下 应该是这样的
recall, would be something like this.
用一个散列和一个新的行有点聪明
A bit clever with one hash and then a new line,
然后也许我们可以做弦的乘法
and then maybe we could do multiplication of strings,
然后以引号-非引号结束此行
and then end this line with quote-unquote.
同样 如果您不熟悉这种语法 也没有关系
Again, it's OK if you're not comfortable with this syntax.
这是我们过去看到的一种更聪明的方法
This was a more clever approach we saw in the past.
但是如果我在这里运行Python of mario.py 我仍然会看到一个包含三个元素的列
But if I run Python of mario.py here, I'll still see a column of three.
但这里重要的是 Main并不
But what's important here is that main does not
需要知道的是Print列的底层实现
need to know that the underlying implementation of print column
已经改变了
has changed.
好吧 让我们过渡到一个不同的维度
Well, let's transition to a different dimension,
如果您愿意 与其打印出这些垂直的砖块 不如让我们
if you will, and rather than print out just these vertical bricks, let's
在游戏中快进到世界的这一部分
fast forward in the game to this part of the world here.
在某些地方 马里奥在天空中遇到了这些砖块
At some part, Mario encounters these bricks in the sky,
如果他从下面跳起来 它们就会变成硬币
that if he jumps up underneath, they become coins.
因此 他获得了他的分数
And so he gains to his score.
但让我们继续 只关注那些硬币
But let's go ahead and focus only on those coins,
让我提议我们打印出来 哦 只是
and let me propose that we print out, oh, just
这里有四个问号
these four question marks here.
让我回到VS Code这里
And let me go back to VS Code here.
让我建议在VS代码中 就像以前一样 我们
And let me propose that within VS Code here, just like before, we
试着把这件事抽象出来
try to abstract this away.
所以让我继续下去 去掉这个版本
So let me go ahead and get rid of this version,
因为我们现在的产出是水平的 而不是垂直的
because we're now going horizontal instead of vertical with our output.
让我说 好吧 打印行四次
And let me just say, well, print row four times.
让我把手头的问题抽象出来
Let me just abstract away the problem at hand.
我还不知道该如何打印这四个问号
I don't know yet how I'm going to print those four question marks,
但让我们将其称为print row 4 我将假设我现在将解决这个问题
but let's call it print row 4, and I'll assume I'll now solve this problem.
现在让我们进入解决这个问题的那个兔子洞
Let's now go down that rabbit hole of solving the problem.
定义一个名为print row的函数
Define a function called print row.
它将采用宽度而不是高度
It's going to take a width instead of a height,
因为它是水平的而不是垂直的
because it's horizontal instead of vertical.
我怎么才能做到这一点？
And how can I do this?
现在 我们有机会做更多的弦乘法
Well now, we have an opportunity to do string multiplication even more
优雅地
elegantly.
我可以说引号-不引号 问号 时间宽度
I can say quote-unquote, question mark, times width.
这是一种非常精美的毕德式的打印方式 否则
And this is a very pretty Pythonic way of printing what could otherwise
做一个循环 这很好 但这是
be a loop, and that's fine, but this is going
继续为我打印那些问号
to go ahead and print those question marks for me.
让我们来做Python of mario.py 回车 现在我得到了四个问号
Let's do Python of mario.py, Enter, and now I've got four question marks.
它远不如更图形化的版本漂亮
It's not nearly as pretty as the more graphical version,
但这至少是迈向
but it is at least a building block toward having
现在是一个可重复使用的函数 如print row
now a reusable function like print row.
我为什么要做这一切？
And why am I doing all this?
比如 为什么我们要过度设计这些问题的解决方案
Like why are we over engineering the solution to these problems
通过打印列和打印行吗？
by having print column and print row?
嗯 这是一种有用的解决问题的技巧
Well, it's a useful problem-solving technique.
一旦你的世界看起来不是一维的
As soon as your world does not look one-dimensional
像这样或者用专栏的版本 但是这个呢？
like this or with the column version, but what about this?
后来在《超级马里奥兄弟》中 马里奥必须跳进这个世界吗？
Later in Super Mario Brothers does Mario have to jump down into this world
那里有很多这样的黑社会障碍
where there's a lot of these underworld barriers.
例如 这里的这个看起来像一个正方形
And this one here, for instance, looks like a square.
它是二维的 有一个高度和一个宽度
It's two-dimensional there's a height and a width to it.
也就是说 有很多不同的方式
And that is to say there's a bunch of different ways
我们可以实施这件事 如果 也许是为了讨论
we could implement this thing if, maybe for discussion,
这就像一个3x3的网格 一个3x3的正方形
it's like a 3-by-3 grid, a 3-by-3 square of sorts.
那么 我们该如何着手解决这个问题呢？
Well, how can we go about solving this here problem?
好吧 让我提议我们回到VS代码
Well, let me propose we come back to VS Code
让我提议我们用几种不同的方式来思考这个问题
and let me propose that we think about this in a couple of different ways.
我可以这样做
I could do this like this.
如果我知道我要去哪里 也许我是一个经验丰富的程序员 让我继续前进
If I know where I'm going, maybe I'm a seasoned programmer, let me go ahead
然后这样做
and do this.
让我打印一个正方形 它的宽度和高度是3
Let me print out a square, the width, and the height of which is 3.
这是一个抽象的概念
That's an abstraction.
我只是认为那一刻是理所当然的
I'm just taking for granted for a moment that there is already
一个名为打印正方形的函数 它的高度为3
a function called print square that's going to be with 3 and height 3
也是
as well.
但总得有人来实施这一点 而目前
But someone's got to implement this, and at the moment,
键盘上只有我一个人 我们继续吧
there's only me at the keyboard, so let's go ahead
并实施那个方块
and implement that square.
让我们继续定义一个名为
Let me go ahead and define a function called
打印具有特定大小的正方形 包括高度和宽度
print square that takes in a specific size, both for height and for width.
这是我们有机会使用其中一些循环的地方
And here's where we have an opportunity to use some of those loops.
我们可以以一种我们还没有使用过的方式来使用这些循环
And we can use those loops in a way we haven't yet.
如果我想打印出所有这些行 但也要打印出所有这些列
If I want to print out all of these rows, but also, all of these columns,
我现在要思考的不仅仅是循环所允许的循环
I now have to think not just cyclically like a loop allows,
但我需要从两个维度来思考
but I need to think two-dimensionally.
如果你熟悉老式打字机甚至打印机
And if you're familiar with like an old school typewriter or even a printer
现在 它通常从上到下打印
nowadays, it generally prints from top to bottom.
因此 即使您有多列 您也可以一次打印一行
So even if you have multiple columns, you print out one line at a time,
当你在那条线上时 打印机或打字机
and while you're on that line, the printer or the typewriter
指纹从左到右
prints from left to right.
这就是你的黑白终端窗口应该具备的心理模型
And that's the mental model to have with your black and white terminal window.
到目前为止 每个示例的所有输出都是从顶部开始的
All of the output for every example thus far starts at the top
跌到了谷底
and goes down to the bottom.
从上到下 从左到右
From top to bottom, left to right.
所以我们必须以同样的方式产生我们的输出 我们的平方
So we have to generate our output, our square in that same way.
所以让我提议我们这样做
So let me propose that we do this.
让我建议我们知道我们需要迭代多次 3次或更多
Let me propose that we know we need to iterate this many times, 3 or more
一般大小
generally size.
那就让我来做吧
So let me do this.
对于尺码范围内的我来说 我需要做三次什么？
For i in the range of size, what do I need to do three times?
好吧 我想打印出什么？
Well, I want to print out what?
1、2、3排砖
1, 2, 3 rows of bricks.
但在每一行砖块中 我想打印什么？
But within each row of bricks, what do I want to print?
具体是1、2、3块砖
1, 2, 3 bricks specifically.
所以如果我们回到我们这里的图表 我
So if we go back to our diagram here and I
规定它确实应该是一个3乘3的正方形 3宽3高
stipulate that it's indeed meant to be a 3-by-3 square, 3 wide and 3 tall,
要打印第一行 我想做什么？
what did I want to do to print the first row?
我想印砖头 砖头
I want to print brick brick, brick.
我想在第二行打印什么？砖头 砖头 砖头
What do I want to print on the second row? brick, brick, brick.
第三排 砖头
And the third row, brick, brick, brick.
所以我做了三件事 三次
So I'm doing three things three times.
必须进行大量的打印工作
There's a lot of printing that must happen.
所以让我回到我的代码 现在让我求婚
So let me go back to my code here and let me propose now
我们想到了我刚刚开始的这个外环
that we think of this outer loop that I've just started
代表我们的每一排
as representing each of our rows.
因为我在一定的尺寸范围内将确保 无论
For i in range of size is going to ensure, no matter
接下来我要做的是 我可以打印出1、2、3行 或者更一般的情况
what I do next, that I can print out 1, 2, 3 rows, or more generally,
大小 其中大小可以是3 但可以更小或更大
size, where size could be 3, but it could be smaller or larger.
我想在每一行上做什么？
What do I want to do on each of the rows?
嗯 就像一台老式打字机或打印机 每一排
Well, just like an old school typewriter or printer, on each row,
我想打印出砖 砖 砖；砖
I want to print out brick, brick, brick; brick, brick, brick; brick, brick,
布里克
brick.
嗯 听起来像是一个循环 某种循环
Well, that sounds like a cycle, some kind of loop.
所以也许我可以在一个循环中有另一个循环
So maybe I can have inside of one loop another loop.
我不想再次使用i 因为我不想使用相同的变量
I don't want to use i again because I don't want to use the same variable
弄乱了我的计数
and mess up my counting.
所以我将按照惯例使用j
So I'm going to by convention use j.
非常常见的用法是先用i 然后用j--也许用k
Very common to use i and then j-- maybe k,
但在那之后 你们不应该一直在彼此的身体里筑巢
but after that, you shouldn't keep nesting inside of each other.
让我继续说 对于大小为2的j
Let me go ahead and say for j in range of size 2,
因为它是一个正方形 然后每一排
because it's a square, and then each of these rows,
让我打印出一个散列 但没有新行 但在每行之后
let me print out a single hash, but no new line, but after each row,
让我只打印一行新行
let me print only a new line.
所以这里发生了很多事情 特别是如果你从来没有
So there's a lot going on here, especially if you've never
触摸到了Python 更不用说循环了 但请注意我在这里也做了什么
touched Python, let alone loops, but notice what I've done here, too,
为了清楚起见 我会补充一些评论
and I'll add some comments for clarity.
对于正方形的每一行 对于每一行的每一块砖 打印砖块
For each row in square, for each brick in row, print brick.
这里是评论的地方 更广泛地说
And here is where comments, and more generally,
伪代码真的可以帮助你向自己和他人解释
pseudocode can really help explain to yourself and to others
您的代码行在做什么
what your lines of code are doing.
在第8行 我从i等于0开始迭代 直到大小
On line 8, I'm iterating from i equals 0 on up to size.
所以0 1 2
So 0, 1, 2.
在第11行 我做了完全相同的事情 但使用了0 1 2中的j
On line 11, I'm doing the exact same thing, but using j from 0, 1, 2.
但这很好 因为我代表了我的每一行
But that's good, because i represents how each of my rows.
当我在这些行中的每一行 在这个外部循环内时
And while I'm on each of those rows, inside of this outer loop,
我要做砖 砖 砖；1 2 3；1 2 3；1 2 3
I'm going to do brick, brick, brick; 1, 2, 3; 1, 2, 3; 1, 2, 3.
但我不希望我的光标一直移动到下一行
But I don't want my cursor to keep moving to the next line
当我在一排的时候 所以我只是在重写那行结尾
while I'm on a row, so I'm just overriding that line ending.
但让我问你一个关于这个团体的问题
But let me ask you a question of the group
现在 为什么我在第16行有一个单独的指纹？
now, why on line 16 do I have a print here all by itself?
为什么我有一个单独的指纹呢？
Why do I have a print all by itself?
请注意 它位于内部循环的下方 但在内部
Notice that it's below the inner loop, but inside
可以说是外环的
of the outer loop, so to speak.
第16行上的循环最终要做什么？
What is that loop on line 16 doing ultimately?
观众：你每完成一行 你就会
AUDIENCE: Every time you finish a line, you
我得在它的末尾加一行
have to add a new line at the end of it.
所以Print 它打印新的一行
So print, it prints a new line.
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
我不想在每一块砖之后都换一条新的线
I don't want a new line after every brick.
我只想在这一排结束时这样做
I only want to do that at the end of the row,
这就是为什么我现在的评论可能是有启发性的
and that's why my comments now are perhaps enlightening.
注意 这里的这个循环只是对行中的每一块砖进行迭代
Notice that this loop here is just iterating for each brick in the row.
可以说 一旦我完成了内部循环
Once I'm done with that inner loop, so to speak,
一旦我完成了这些突出显示的行 按照伊夫林的观点
once I'm done with these highlighted lines here, to Evelyn's point,
我需要打印出一个空白的新行
I need to print out one blank new line.
我们以前没有这样做过 但是当您不带参数地调用print时
And we've not done this before, but when you call print with no arguments,
你得到的只是自动结束的行号
all you get is that automatic line ending,
光标移动到下一行的反斜杠n
the backslash n where the cursor moves to the next line.
所以如果我现在返回到我的终端窗口并运行mario.py
So if I now go back to my terminal window and run mario.py,
我想我应该买一个3乘3的正方形
I think I should get a 3-by-3 square.
而且它在我的屏幕上看起来不太像一个正方形
And it doesn't quite look like a square on my screen
因为这些散列比它们的宽度稍高一些 但事实上
because these hashes are a little taller than they are wide, but it is, in fact,
3x3
3-by-3.
但让我提议 就像我们在这里一贯做的那样 如何
But let me propose, as we've always done here, how
我们可能会进一步收紧这一代码
we might tighten up this code further.
为了清楚起见 让我暂时抛开我的评论
Just for clarity's sake, let me get rid of my comments for a moment
这样我们就可以看到我们总共有多少行代码
just so we can see how many lines of code we have total.
让我提议我们或许可以这样做
And let me propose that we maybe do this.
让我提议 你知道吗 这个内部循环
Let me propose that, you know what, this inner loop,
尤其是如果你在包装上有困难的话
especially if you're having trouble wrapping
你的思想围绕着另一个循环中的一个循环
your mind around one loop inside of another loop,
你并不完全需要它
you don't strictly need it.
如果我们再来一次这个把戏呢？
What if we do this trick again?
如果我们在外部循环中打印出来 并且只有每个循环
What if we print out inside of the outer and only loop each
这些散列的次数是我们想要的次数的倍数吗？
of those hashes times the number of times we want them?
我们从早期的方法中获得灵感
We draw inspiration from an earlier approach
现在我们在mario.py上运行Python 同样的结果
and we run Python now of mario.py, same result,
但现在 Print Square真的很漂亮 很紧凑
but now, print square is really nice and compact.
它有一个显式循环 并且仍在打印输出
It has one explicit loop, and it's still printing out
使用字符串乘法一次将该行上的所有散列相乘
using string multiplication all of the hashes at once on that row.
如果您喜欢抽象 并且您想更多地考虑
If you like abstraction and you'd like to wrap your mind more around what
代码是这样做的 好吧 让我们这样做
the code is doing, well, let's do this.
如果你不太清楚发生了什么事
If you're not quite clear on what's going on,
让我们建议您实现一个名为
let's propose that you implement a function called
打印行 传入大小
print row, passing in size.
让我建议这个打印行函数 它只接受这个宽度
And let me propose that this print row function, it simply take in that width
并多次打印出单个散列的次数
and print out the individual hash times that many times.
换句话说 这是一个抽象的机会 由此 嗯 什么
In other words, here's an opportunity for abstraction, whereby, well, what
是指打印一行吗？
does it mean to print a row?
嗯 当您实现Print Square时
Well, when you're implementing print square,
我真的不在乎打印一行意味着什么
I don't really care what it means to print a row,
我只想知道有没有人负责打印这行
I just need to know that someone's taking care of printing the row.
您完全可以将责任转嫁给另一个函数
You can pass the buck to another function altogether.
打印行是如何工作的？
And how does print row work?
它可以使用for循环 它可以使用这个字符串乘法技巧
Well, it could use a for loop, it could use this string multiplication trick.
这是一种采用更大程序的方法--这可能是
This is a way to take a larger program-- and this is probably the most
到目前为止我们已经看到了一个复杂的问题--
complicated one we've looked at thus far--
然后把它分解成这些更小的组件 一旦组装好
and to decompose it into these smaller components, that once assembled,
实现你的最终想法
achieve your final idea.
看不到任何问题 我们对循环的了解就到此结束
Seeing no questions, that's the end of our look at loops
在Python中 这种一次又一次循环地做事情的能力
in Python, this ability to do things cyclically again and again,
当我们把它们和条件句结合起来时 这种能力
and when we combine those with conditionals, this ability
提问和回答问题 并将它们与我们的函数和变量相结合
to ask and answer questions and combine them with our functions and variables,
我们现在真的拥有了大部分的构建块
we really now have most of the building blocks
我们需要解决更大、更有趣、更多
we need to solve much larger, much more interesting, much
更多的私人问题
more personal questions.
因此 在接下来的几周里 我们将开始确切地看到可能会出现什么问题
So in the weeks to come, we'll start to see exactly what could go wrong,
虽然 当我们这样做的时候 但我们会为你介绍
though, when we do so, but we'll introduce you
到所有更多的工具 您可以通过这些工具来解决这些相同的问题
to all the more tools via which you can troubleshoot those same problems.